COLTON OGDEN: All right.
科尔顿·奥格登：好的
Good evening, everybody.
大家晚上好
Welcome back to GD50.
欢迎回到GD50
This is lecture six.
这是第六讲
And today we're going to be venturing out of the 8-bit world
今天 我们将冒险走出8位世界
and back into a more modern era of gaming.
回到一个更现代的游戏时代
We're talking about Angry Birds today.
今天我们要谈论的是《愤怒的小鸟》
I have pretty fond memories of Angry Birds, actually.
事实上 我对《愤怒的小鸟》有着非常美好的回忆
It was the first mobile game that I remember
这是我记忆中的第一款手机游戏
playing where I realized that mobile was actually a viable platform for gaming.
在那里我意识到移动设备实际上是一个可行的游戏平台
I played it, I think, back in 2009, was when it was first released.
我想 早在2009年 也就是它第一次发行的时候 我就玩过了
And I really enjoyed it.
我真的很享受
It has a very simple formula.
它有一个非常简单的公式
The goal, if you're unfamiliar, is you have
如果你不熟悉 我们的目标是你有
birds that you control by a sling shot on the left side of the screen.
你可以通过屏幕左侧的弹弓来控制鸟儿
And then these pigs that have stolen your eggs,
然后这些偷了你卵子的猪
you're trying to destroy them or kill them
你在试图摧毁他们或杀死他们
by knocking down their fortresses made out of various materials, wood, glass,
通过推倒他们用各种材料 木头 玻璃
metal.
金属
And you get a few different bird types.
你会得到几种不同类型的鸟
But the gist of it is, basically, just sling shot a bird into some structure,
但它的大意是 基本上 只是把一只鸟扔进某种结构中
knock it down.
把它打倒
And the whole entire underlying mechanism
以及整个潜在的机制
for how things work is via a physics engine,
因为事物是如何通过物理引擎工作的
which we'll talk about today in lecture, called Box2D Probably
今天我们将在课程中讨论它 可能名为Box2D
the most ubiquitous 2D physics engine.
最普遍的2D物理引擎
But that's the overall structure of the game.
但这就是游戏的总体结构
It's literally just throwing things into structures, knocking them down.
从字面上讲 就是把东西扔进建筑物里 把它们推倒
And then that tactile and fun game play makes for really great mobile gaming.
然后 触觉和有趣的游戏玩法造就了真正伟大的手机游戏
And I enjoyed it a lot back in the day.
我以前也很喜欢这样的比赛
This is a screenshot of the first level in the first Angry Birds, which
这是第一部《愤怒的小鸟》第一关的截图
most people I think have probably seen.
我想大多数人可能都见过
This is a sample from one of their newer games.
这是他们的一款新游戏中的一个样本
As you can see, it's taken a whole new layer here.
正如你所看到的 这里已经有了一个全新的层面
There's stone and a bunch of intricately varying structures and new creatures
有石头和一堆错综复杂的结构和新生物
and stuff like that.
诸如此类的事情
The game has changed a lot, but the formula has stayed the same.
比赛已经发生了很大的变化 但规则并没有改变
And today we'll explore the foundation of what makes this game work.
今天 我们将探索这款游戏赖以运行的基础
And the topics today, a smaller than usual.
而今天的话题 比平时要小一些
But Box2D, we can consider as being a pretty large topic.
但是Box2D 我们可以认为是一个相当大的话题
We'll be talking about Box2D, which is the physics
我们将谈论Box2D 也就是物理学
engine we'll be using today in lecture.
我们将在今天的课程中使用发动机
And via Love2D, which has its own wrapper for Box2D.
还有通过Love2D 它有自己的Box2D包装器
And we'll also talk a little bit about mouse input, which you haven't really
我们还将讨论鼠标输入 这是您还没有真正了解到的
done a lot.
做了很多事
But it's very apt, especially in the context of mobile gaming.
但这是非常恰当的 特别是在手机游戏的背景下
Because mouse input and touch input are synonymous.
因为鼠标输入和触摸输入是同义词
But first, let's get a lecture demo.
但首先 让我们来看一段演讲演示
If we have a volunteer come up on stage to showcase
如果我们有一位志愿者上台展示
what I've put together here.
我在这里所做的一切
So let me make sure I'm in the right directory here.
所以让我确保我在这里的目录中是正确的
So whenever you're ready, go ahead and press Enter.
因此 只要您准备好了 就继续并按Enter键
So this is a little demo I put together to demonstrate the concepts we'll
这是我放在一起的一个小演示 用来演示我们将
talk about today in class.
在课堂上谈论今天
This is just the Start screen, but it already
这只是开始屏幕 但它已经
shows Box2D representing a bunch of these square shaped aliens, which
显示了代表一群方形外星人的Box2D 它
we'll actually be what we're trying to target in the game.
我们实际上将成为我们在游戏中试图瞄准的目标
But notice that they all fell and had their own collision
但请注意 它们都坠落了 并有自己的碰撞
and their own physics that took place, and I didn't have to manually code
以及它们自己的物理过程 我不必手动编写代码
rotation and stuff like this.
旋转和诸如此类的东西
This is all stuff that Box2D takes care of for us.
这些都是Box2D为我们打理的东西
And we'll see it used to great effect soon.
我们很快就会看到它被用来产生巨大的效果
If you go ahead and just click anywhere on the screen,
如果你继续点击屏幕上的任何地方
we'll go to the main part of the game.
我们将进入比赛的主要部分
So this is a very simple representation of what Angry Birds is.
这是《愤怒的小鸟》的一个非常简单的描述
You start on the left side of the screen.
您从屏幕的左侧开始
You have a bird, in this case an alien, we
你有一只鸟 在这种情况下是外星人 我们
used a free art pack that uses aliens instead of birds,
使用了一个使用外星人而不是鸟类的免费艺术包
but it's the same concept.
但这是同一个概念
You have an alien that you can click and drag.
你有一个外星人 你可以点击和拖动
So if you click it and then drag around, you
因此 如果您单击它 然后四处拖动 您就可以
can see the trajectory that you'll have when you let go of the mouse.
可以看到当你松开鼠标时你将拥有的轨迹
So we're simulating where it's going to go via these purple circles.
所以我们通过这些紫色的圆圈来模拟它的去向
And then the goal in Angry Birds is to throw the bird into,
然后《愤怒的小鸟》的目标是把小鸟扔进
or the alien, into the fortress guarding the pigs,
或者外星人 进入守卫着猪的堡垒
or in this case, square shaped aliens.
或者在这种情况下 是方形的外星人
So if you go ahead and just launch the bird by letting go of the mouse
因此 如果您继续 只需松开鼠标即可将鸟发射出去
you'll see.
你终究会明白的
Oh, there we go.
哦 又来了
And we knocked down the.
然后我们推倒了
OK.
好的
What happened was we shot the alien into the structure.
事情是这样的 我们把外星人射进了建筑里
It destroyed one of the wooden blocks guarding the other alien.
它摧毁了守卫另一个外星人的一块木块
And then, as soon as that happened, the top box,
然后 这一切一发生 顶部的盒子
because these are all being simulated via Box2D's physics engine,
因为这些都是通过Box2D的物理引擎模拟的
that other box was detected as being unsupported.
另一个盒子被检测为不受支持
So it fell down, it hit the other alien.
所以它掉了下来 撞到了另一个外星人
And we've coded it so that when a collision occurs
我们已经对它进行了编码 这样当发生碰撞时
between an obstacle and our alien of sufficient speed,
在障碍物和速度足够快的外星人之间
it should kill the alien.
它应该会杀死外星人
Which is how it works in Angry Birds.
这就是《愤怒的小鸟》的工作原理
So if you'll try it again.
所以如果你愿意再试一次
And this time we hit both of those at the same time.
这一次 我们同时击中了这两个目标
So it triggered both of those being deleted.
因此 它引发了这两个被删除的消息
But this guy is still alive.
但这家伙还活着
So after it stops moving, which is similar to how
所以在它停止运动后 这类似于如何
it behaves in the original game, it's going to let us try again to shoot.
它表现在最初的游戏中 它会让我们再次尝试射击
So if we try one more time.
所以如果我们再试一次
And then we launch and hit it, we kill it and then we get a victory.
然后我们发射并击中它 我们杀死它 然后我们就取得了胜利
So that's the overall underlying foundation for what Angry Birds is.
这就是《愤怒的小鸟》的整体基础
Obviously we're using a very simple representation.
显然 我们使用的是一个非常简单的表示法
It doesn't have a lot of the frill that Angry Birds does.
它不像《愤怒的小鸟》那样有太多的装饰
But we could easily build upon this and create a fully fleshed out
但我们可以很容易地在此基础上创建一个完全充实的
game very similar to Angry Birds.
这款游戏与《愤怒的小鸟》非常相似
So thanks, Steven.
所以谢谢你 史蒂文
I appreciate the demonstration.
我很感谢你的示范
So that's our goal today.
这就是我们今天的目标
We'll be talking about how to construct a very basic but functional simulation
我们将讨论如何构建一个非常基本但功能强大的模拟
of what Angry Birds is at its core.
《愤怒的小鸟》的核心是什么
Which is just flinging things into obstacles, destroying them,
这只是把东西扔进障碍物 摧毁它们
and ultimately destroying the things that they're protecting,
最终摧毁他们所保护的东西
the aliens, the pigs that are in the base game.
外星人 基地游戏中的猪
So here's a shot of what the different sprite sheets we're going to be using
下面是我们将使用的不同精灵床单的快照
are.
是
There's a really great sprite sheet that I got off of Open Game Art.
我从《开放游戏艺术》上学到了一张很棒的精灵单子
Kenny is the artist.
肯尼是艺术家
He makes a lot of great art.
他创作了很多伟大的艺术作品
If you notice, it's very similar looking to the art
如果你注意到了 它看起来很像艺术
that we use in the Mario lecture.
我们在马里奥的演讲中用到的
Actually, it's the same artist.
实际上 是同一个艺术家
So if you're ever looking for assets, he's got a ton of awesome assets
所以 如果你在寻找资产 他有一大堆了不起的资产
on open game art.
关于开放游戏艺术
So we have a set of aliens, square and round shaped.
所以我们有一组外星人 方形和圆形的
I decided just arbitrarily we made the round shaped aliens the birds.
我武断地决定 我们把圆形的外星人做成鸟
So we shoot those into the structures that are
所以我们把它们射入结构中
protecting the square shaped aliens.
保护正方形的外星人
The square shape aliens will be the bad guys in this case.
在这种情况下 正方形的外星人将是坏人
And then we have another sprite sheet down here below on the left side.
然后我们有另一张精灵纸在下面的左边
Which just, I used the tile here just to make a ground element.
只是 我用这里的瓷砖做了一个地面元素
The rest of these you could easily include in the game if you wanted to,
剩下的这些你可以很容易地包括在游戏中 如果你想的话
but we're only using the ground here.
但我们只是在使用这里的地面
And then notice here, we have this large sprite sheet
然后注意这里 我们有一个很大的精灵纸
which has a bunch of different shapes and sizes of materials.
它有一堆不同形状和大小的材料
The whole sprite sheet comes with metal and explosive and glass sheets as well.
整个精灵薄片都有金属、炸药和玻璃薄片
But just for simplicity we only use the wood here.
但为了简单起见 我们只使用这里的木头
But notice that we have entirely whole pieces
但请注意 我们有完整的部件
and then we have pieces that are partially destroyed
然后我们有部分被摧毁的碎片
and then pieces that are hollow.
然后是中空的碎片
You could easily model all of these in your game and use them.
您可以很容易地在游戏中对所有这些进行建模并使用它们
But we only decided to use just a couple of these,
但我们只决定使用其中的几个
which was just the horizontal and the vertical ones that
只有水平的和垂直的
are completely whole.
是完全完整的
These, unfortunately, don't have quite the same systematic layout
不幸的是 它们的系统布局并不完全相同
as the sprites that we used before.
就像我们以前用过的精灵
They're not laid out in a grid evenly spaced.
它们不是均匀分布在网格中的
So in this case, in util dot Lua, I ended up hard
所以在这种情况下 在util dotLua中 我最终很难
coding the different XY width and height quads
对不同的XY宽度和高度四元组进行编码
for each of these, which is what you have to do in a situation
对于其中的每一个 这是你在一种情况下必须做的
where you're interacting not with tiles per se,
在这里 你不是在与瓷砖本身互动
but with more organic shaped objects.
但有了更多有机形状的物体
So it can take a little more time to end up
所以它可能需要更多的时间才能结束
constructing all of the quads for your objects
为您的对象构建所有四边形
when you have a sprite sheet like this.
当你有这样一张精灵床单的时候
But, fortunately, you only have to do it once.
但是 幸运的是 你只需要做一次
Here's a few useful links before we get started in talking about what Box2D is
在我们开始讨论Box2D是什么之前 这里有一些有用的链接
and how to use it, and basically how it's called love dot
以及如何使用它 以及它基本上是如何被称为爱情圆点的
physics, effectively, in love2D.
物理学 有效地 在爱的2D中
The first two links are documentation for love 2D,
前两个链接是LOVE 2D的文档
what the functions and objects are that we'll be talking about.
我们将要讨论的函数和对象是什么
And a simple tutorial that talks about how to make a ball
还有一个简单的教程 讲述了如何制造一个球
bounce in love 2D using Box2D.
使用Box2D在爱情2D中弹跳
The third is a great resource that I used actually
第三个是我实际使用的一个很好的资源
to learn most of what I know about Box2D, especially
要了解我对Box2D的大部分了解 特别是
in the context of this lecture.
在这堂课的背景下
So it talks about a lot of different concepts.
所以它谈到了很多不同的概念
It talks about all the things that we'll be talking about.
它谈到了我们将要讨论的所有事情
And then it goes into a lot more detail about how
然后 它将更详细地介绍如何
you can go about constructing a lot of really cool, crazy things like tanks
你可以着手建造很多非常酷、很疯狂的东西 比如坦克
and pulleys and a whole bunch of different things
滑轮和一大堆不同的东西
that are worth looking into if you're looking into potentially making
如果您正在寻找潜在的
a physics based game.
一款基于物理的游戏
Obviously we won't be going into things of that complexity here.
显然 我们不会在这里讨论这种复杂的事情
But you could easily do it with Box2D.
但你可以用Box2D很容易地做到这一点
It makes it very, very possible.
这使得这一点非常非常有可能
So the very first thing that we should talk
所以我们要谈的第一件事
about when we want to construct a game, or simulation,
关于我们什么时候想要构建一个游戏或模拟
or whatever we want to do, with Box2D is we
或者无论我们想做什么 使用Box2D是我们
need some sort of system that will actually perform the simulation for us.
需要某种系统来为我们实际执行模拟
And the fundamental core of what a Box2D app or game is, the core is the world
Box2D应用程序或游戏的基本核心是世界
object.
对象
So there is a world that you can think of as sort of being your world,
所以有一个世界 你可以把它想象成你的世界
but what it effectively is is a machine that simulates all of the pieces
但它实际上是一台模拟所有部件的机器
that you've told it interact with each other in Box2D.
你已经告诉它在Box2D中相互作用
So Box2D has a set of objects called fixtures and bodies.
因此 Box2D具有一组称为灯具和实体的对象
Those perform the physical interactions.
它们执行物理上的互动
And it's up to the world to update all of those
全世界都有责任更新这些
and apply the relevant forces and physics calculations
并应用相关的力和物理计算
that resolve collisions and do all sorts of things.
解决碰撞和做各种事情
All of the things that Box2D does for us, the world
Box2D为我们和世界所做的一切
takes care of this for us.
会帮我们解决这件事
So we don't have to manually go through and update every single object
所以我们不需要手动检查和更新每一个对象
with its velocity that we've done before and check for collisions.
我们之前做过的 并检查碰撞
The world does this for us, and resolves them
世界为我们做了这些 并解决了这些问题
based on how we tell it to resolve them.
基于我们如何告诉它去解决它们
And the world also possesses, like an actual world
这个世界也拥有 就像一个真实的世界
would, gravity on the x and y-axis.
重力在x轴和y轴上
In this case, we have gravity applied on the y-axis going down,
在这个例子中 重力作用在y轴上
so it's a positive value.
所以它是正值
We set it to 300 in this distro, but you can set it to whatever you want.
我们在这个发行版中将其设置为300 但您可以将其设置为任何您想要的值
Setting a lower gravity would have the effect
设定一个较低的重力会产生这样的效果
of making it feel like we're on the moon or something.
让我们感觉像是在月球上
Making it feel like we're on a different planet.
感觉我们在另一个星球
So that's what the world is.
原来世界就是这样
The world simulates everything.
世界模拟一切
And we'll go through just a few terms here
我们在这里讲几个术语
before we look at some source code.
在我们看一些源代码之前
But there's a few terms that we need to understand before we can really
但在我们真正理解
understand what Box2D is doing.
了解Box2D在做什么
And this is the function that we use to create a new world in love2D.
这是我们用来在love2D中创建一个新世界的函数
Very simple, love dot physics dot new world.
很简单 爱点物理点新世界
And this love dot physics is just a name space that
这个爱点物理学只是一个命名空间
encapsulates all of the Box2D functions and objects that love2D has access to.
封装了love2D可以访问的所有Box2D函数和对象
So anything that you see in love dot physics is effectively
所以你在爱点物理学中看到的任何东西
a wrapper for Box2D.
Box2D的包装器
And to clarify about Box2D, Box2D is just a library that's written in C++
为了澄清Box2D Box2D只是一个用C++编写的库
that you can plug-in pretty much anywhere you want to.
你可以在任何你想插入的地方插入
Unity uses it and, actually, most 2D game engines
Unity使用它 实际上 大多数2D游戏引擎都使用它
that I've ever seen including Live GDX, for example, which is a very large Java
包括Live GDX 这是一个非常大的Java
2D game framework uses Box2D.
2D游戏框架使用Box2D
You can use it anywhere.
你可以在任何地方使用它
In this case we're using love2D's own wrapper for it.
在这种情况下 我们使用love2D自己的包装器
So the people that created love 2D, they took Box2D
所以创造爱情2D的人 他们采用了Box2D
and then they just put a bunch of Lua functions
然后他们只需要把一组Lua函数
around them, around all the objects and functions
围绕着它们 围绕着所有的对象和功能
to make it possible to use it in the same style
以使其可以在相同的样式中使用
that we use the rest of the framework.
我们使用框架的其余部分
This is how you create a new world.
这就是你创造一个新世界的方式
This is the first step in getting your Box2D simulation working.
这是使Box2D模拟工作的第一步
So any questions so far as to how we can get that going?
那么 到目前为止 我们对如何实现这一目标有什么问题吗？
OK.
好的
So beyond the world object, which is the foundation, sort of sets up our stage,
因此 超越世界对象 这是基础 某种程度上搭建了我们的舞台
you can think of it as our stage, we need bodies
你可以把它想象成我们的舞台 我们需要身体
to actually interact with each other.
才能真正地相互影响
So a body is just an abstract container.
所以身体只是一个抽象的容器
It basically holds a position and a velocity.
它基本上保持着一个位置和一个速度
And you attach things to it via what are called fixtures
你通过所谓的固定装置将东西固定在它上面
that allow you to give the body a shape, and therefore a collision box,
它允许你给身体一个形状 因此是一个碰撞框
and therefore allow it to interact with other things.
从而允许它与其他事物相互作用
But a body is essentially all the disparate things in your scene interact
但身体本质上是场景中所有不同的东西相互作用
with each other and move around.
彼此在一起 四处走动
And so to create a new body we just do love dot physics dot new body.
因此 为了创造一个新的身体 我们只是喜欢点物理 点新的身体
We pass in the world, so therefore when we do this,
我们在这个世界上走过 所以当我们这样做的时候
the world has a reference to this body now.
现在 全世界都提到了这个机构
And every time we call update on our world, which
每次我们呼吁更新我们的世界 这是
we'll see in the source code, it will know, OK,
我们会在源代码中看到 它会知道 好的
I have a reference to this body, perform all of the relevant checks
我有这个机构的参考资料 进行所有相关的检查
on the collision for that body and all the fixtures that it contains.
关于该车身及其所包含的所有夹具的碰撞
Update its position, updates velocity, and so forth.
更新其位置、更新速度等
And not only a world, but it also gets an x and a y,
不仅是一个世界 而且还有一个x和y
which will place it in the world on instantiation.
这将把它放在实例化的世界中
The last parameter here, type.
这里的最后一个参数是输入
There are three fundamental types of bodies
有三种基本类型的物体
which we'll see in love 2D, static, dynamic, and kinematic.
我们将在爱情中看到2D的、静态的、动态的和运动学的
And that basically influences how it'll interact with the other objects,
这基本上影响了它与其他物体的互动方式
the other bodies, in our scene.
其他身体 在我们的场景中
So we have the world, which encapsulates everything,
所以我们有这个世界 它囊括了一切
all the bodies, all the fixtures.
所有的身体 所有的固定装置
And then we have the bodies, which are the entities in our game world
然后我们有身体 这是我们游戏世界中的实体
that have position and velocity, effectively.
它们有位置和速度
The last key ingredient here that will allow
最后一个关键因素是
us to create interactions between the bodies that we have are fixtures.
在我们的身体之间创造相互作用是固定的
And fixtures, all a fixture is, is this abstract object
而夹具 夹具的全部 就是这个抽象的对象
that will allow you to attach a shape to a body.
它可以让你把一个形状附加到一个物体上
So bodies are shapeless by default. They don't have a shape.
所以身体是无形的 它们没有形状
They are just a container that has position velocity, effectively.
它们只是一个有效地具有位置速度的容器
But they don't interact with anything else.
但它们不与其他任何东西相互作用
And they don't know how to interact with anything else
他们不知道如何与其他东西互动
until you give them a fixture.
直到你给他们一个固定的
And the fixture you will give the body and a shape.
和夹具你会给身体和形状
So for example, if you want the bird that we
比如说 如果你想要一只鸟
were looking at earlier, the alien, the round alien, we create a body for it
我们之前看到的外星人 圆形的外星人 我们为它创造了一个身体
in our world, which doesn't mean anything yet.
在我们的世界里这还不意味着什么
But we say, I'm going to attach a fixture to that alien.
但是我们说 我要给那个外星人装一个固定装置
I'm going to give it a circle shape.
我要给它一个圆形
And it'll then know whenever it performs any calculations,
它就会知道无论何时进行任何计算
that that alien should interact with things as if it were round.
外星人应该和圆形物体互动
And therefore trigger collisions based on a circular hitbox,
从而触发基于圆形命中盒的碰撞
as opposed to a rectangular or polygonal hitbox, as we'll see.
而不是长方形或多边形的击中盒
Fixtures, in addition to attaching shapes
固定装置 除了附加形状
to bodies, which will, as said here, influence
到身体 这将 正如这里所说 影响
how they collide with other bodies, they have density, which we'll see.
它们如何与其他物体碰撞 它们有密度 我们会看到
So that things with higher density obviously
所以密度大的物体
will fall faster, or not fall faster, but they will influence things
会下降得更快 或者不会下降得更快 但它们会影响事情
as if they have more weight.
就像他们有更多的重量
They will push things farther when they collide with them.
当它们与物体碰撞时 它们会把物体推得更远
They also have friction and they have restitution.
他们也有摩擦 他们有恢复
Restitution is bounciness.
喘息是有弹性的
So if something, if we had our alien, no restitution when it hits the ground
所以如果有什么东西 如果我们有外星人 当它落地的时候
it'll just fall flat.
它会失败的
But if we give it a higher restitution it
但如果我们给它更高的回报
will actually bounce when it hits the ground.
会在落地时反弹
And therefore interact with the world a little bit differently.
因此与世界的互动略有不同
So when we want to take a fixture and apply a shape to a body,
因此 当我们想要一个固定装置 并将一个形状应用到身体上时
we have a few different shapes that we can
我们可以有几种不同的形状
apply to it that are given to us by default in love 2D.
适用于在2D爱中默认给予我们的爱
So circle shape, rectangle shape, edge shape.
所以圆形 长方形 边形
These are just, effectively, how we define how
这些就是我们如何有效地定义
our bodies interact with other bodies.
我们的身体与其他身体相互作用
How, for example, if it's something that's circular
例如 如果它是圆形的东西
it should roll when it's moving along the ground.
当它沿着地面移动时 它应该滚动
Or when it hits something the corner obviously of it
或者当它击中某物时 显然是在它的一角
won't hit something because it's rounded, as opposed to something
不会打到什么东西 因为它是圆角的 而不是
that has a square hit box, it'll affect things in a slightly different way.
有一个方形的点击框 它会以一种略有不同的方式影响事情
And we can define arbitrarily shaped hit boxes, thanks to the polygon shape.
我们可以定义任意形状的点击框 这要归功于多边形
If we want something to be shaped like a pentagon, for example,
例如 如果我们想要一个形状像五角形的东西
and have it roll around and behave like such,
让它像这样滚来滚去
we can just define a polygon via a set of vertices.
我们可以通过一组顶点来定义一个多边形
And then affix that to a body and it will
然后把它贴在身体上 它就会
behave as if it were pentagon shaped.
表现得好像它是五角形的
And this is how you would instantiate just as we've
这就是您将如何实例化 就像我们
seen with love dot physics dot new world and love dot physics dot new body,
看到了爱点物理点新世界和爱点物理点新身体
love dot physics dot new fixture takes in a body and a shape,
爱点物理点新的夹具以身体和形状
and will apply that shape to the body.
并将该形状应用到身体上
And the world after that will know exactly how to collide with things.
而在那之后的世界将确切地知道如何与事物碰撞
And so the last thing, the last slide we'll
所以最后一件事 最后一张幻灯片
look at here before we start looking at source code
在我们开始查看源代码之前 请先看这里
is what the different body types are.
不同的体型是什么
So I alluded to having three different body types before, static, dynamic,
所以我之前提到过有三种不同的体型 静态的 动态的
and kinematic.
和运动学的
So a static body will exist in our world but not actually be affected by gravity
因此 我们的世界中将存在一个静止的物体 但实际上不会受到重力的影响
or the collision of anything else.
或者其他任何东西的碰撞
Things can hit it and bounce off of it and do their own thing,
事物可以撞击它 然后弹出来 做它们自己的事情
but the static body will never be influenced by something else.
但静态的身体永远不会受到其他东西的影响
It exists as some sort of permanent structure, almost like the ground.
它以某种永久结构的形式存在 几乎就像地面一样
You don't really affect the ground by moving into it and bouncing into it,
你并不会通过移动和弹跳来影响地面
unless you do it with enough force.
除非你用足够的力
But in our Box2D world, a static body cannot be influenced by anything else.
但是在我们的Box2D世界中 一个静态的身体不可能受到任何其他东西的影响
A dynamic body is the opposite.
动态的身体是相反的
It has the full simulation of Box2D.
它具有Box2D的完整模拟
Gravity affects it, things collide into it, it will bounce off of them.
重力影响它 物体碰撞它 它会反弹
It'll do what you would expect a normal body to do.
它会做你所期望的一个正常的身体做
If I throw a ball in this room and it hits the wall, it's a dynamic body.
如果我在这个房间里扔一个球 它碰到了墙 这是一个动态物体
The walls are the static bodies in this case.
在这种情况下 墙壁是静态物体
And then a kinematic body is a hybrid between the two.
运动体是两者的混合体
It's something that can move and can rotate and do things,
它是一种可以移动 可以旋转和做一些事情的东西
but it's not influenced by other objects colliding with it.
但不受其他物体碰撞的影响
So, for example, if I have a platform that's just spinning indefinitely,
举个例子 如果我有一个平台 它不停地旋转
but it's not being affected by gravity and it doesn't move when I hit it,
但它不受重力的影响 当我撞击它时 它不会移动
that's a kinematic body.
这是一个运动体
It's still moving and it's semi-static and it influences other things,
它仍然在移动 它是半静态的 它影响着其他东西
but it's not purely static.
但它不是纯粹的静态的
It does have a little bit of behavior that it can grant it.
它确实有一点行为可以授予它
So let's go ahead and look at a few examples
让我们继续看几个例子
now and see how this actually looks in code.
现在来看看这在代码中是什么样子的
So I'm going to go into an example, if you're looking in the distro,
所以我将进入一个例子 如果你在发行版中查找
there is an example called static.
有一个叫做静态的例子
So we'll take a look here and see what a static body looks like in our scene.
我们来看看在我们的场景中 静态物体是什么样子的
And for all of these examples leading up to Angry Birds,
对于所有这些导致愤怒的小鸟的例子
we're just going to render everything with shapes for simplicity.
为了简单起见 我们将用形状来渲染所有东西
But this, as anti-climactic as it is, is a full Box2D world
但这是一个完整的Box2D世界
with just a single static body.
只有一个静止的身体
And it's just this square here, colored white.
就是这个正方形 白色的
The static body doesn't move, it doesn't do anything.
静止的物体不动 什么也不做
Nothing can influence how it moves or behaves.
没有什么能影响它的动作或行为
But it exists in our world as a permanent fixture.
但它在我们的世界里是一个永久的固定装置
And if we had dynamic bodies and we threw a dynamic body at it,
如果我们有一个动态的物体 我们把它扔到一个动态的物体上
for example, the dynamic body would bounce off,
比如说 动态物体会弹开
the static body would stay there permanently.
静止的物体将永久留在那里
So let's go ahead and take a look at what
让我们继续下去 看看是什么
the source code looks like for that.
其源代码如下所示
So I'm here in main dot Lua of our static file.
所以我现在在静态文件的main点Lua中
And just as we've seen before, we needed to find a world.
就像我们以前看到的 我们需要找到一个世界
So I have a world here on line 45.
所以我在第45行有一个世界
Love dot physics dot new world, no x-able gravity,
爱点物理点点新世界 没有x-可引力
but we are going to have 300 units of positive gravity on the y-axis, which
但是我们在y轴上会有300个单位的正重力
is going from top to bottom.
是从上到下
We need a body for our square that's in our game world, our static square.
我们的方块需要一个在游戏世界中的实体 我们的静态方块
So we're going to go ahead and define a new body here.
因此 我们将继续在这里定义一个新的身体
Love dot physics dot new body takes in the world,
爱点物理点新身体走进世界
recall, because that's how our world's going to have a reference to that body,
回想一下 因为这就是我们的世界将如何引用那个身体
doesn't know about it unless we pass it into here, our new body constructor.
不知道 除非我们把它传到这里 我们的新身体构造者
And then I'm just going to put it right in the middle of the screen.
然后我就把它放在屏幕中央
So virtual width divided by 2 and virtual height divided by 2.
所以虚拟宽度除以2 虚拟高度除以2
The difference between Box2D bodies and things
Box2D物体与物体的区别
that we've drawn before or seen before is
我们以前画过或见过的东西是
that everything is defined by its center point, as opposed to its top left.
一切都是由它的中心点定义的 而不是它的左上角
So I'm able to say virtual width divided by 2
所以我可以说虚拟宽度除以2
and virtual height divided by 2 here.
这里用虚拟高度除以2
But I don't actually need to say virtual width divided by 2 minus whatever
但实际上我不需要说虚拟宽度除以2减去任何东西
the half of that square is.
那个正方形的一半是
By default, the center point is the XY of that object.
默认情况下 中心点是该对象的XY
And this last string here in the constructor for our new body, static,
我们新Body的构造函数中的最后一个字符串是静态的
tells the constructor that this is going to be a static body specifically,
告诉构造函数这将是一个特定的静态主体
not a dynamic body and not a kinematic body.
既不是动力学物体 也不是运动学物体
So we have a body and it's static, but it doesn't have a shape,
所以我们有一个物体 它是静态的 但它没有形状
it doesn't really know how to interact with anything else in our world.
它真的不知道如何与我们世界中的任何其他东西互动
So we're going to give it a--
所以我们要给它一个--
we're going to create a new shape first.
我们首先要创建一个新的形状
So love gives us a few functions in the form of new X shape.
因此 爱以新的X字形的形式给了我们一些功能
We have new rectangle shape, new circle shape, new edge shape,
我们有新的矩形 新的圆形 新的边缘形状
a few other ones.
还有其他几个
We're just going to create a new rectangle of width and height of 10.
我们只需要创建一个宽度和高度为10的新矩形
So that's what the 10 and 10 are here.
这就是10号和10号在这里的原因
Then we're going to create a new fixture.
然后我们将创建一个新的灯具
We're going to affix the box shape to our body with this function.
我们要用这个功能把盒子的形状固定在我们的身体上
And then once we do that, all we have to do is then render a polygon with fill
一旦我们这样做了 我们所要做的就是用填充渲染一个多边形
and then we get the coordinates for our-- or the vertices for our polygon
然后我们得到我们的--或我们的多边形的顶点的坐标
by saying, body get world points.
通过这句话 身体得到了世界积分
So that's a function off of any Box2D body
所以这是任何Box2D实体的函数
that will basically get where it is in the world and all of its vertices.
这基本上会得到它在世界上的位置和它的所有顶点
And then you just pass in the shape that you want to get the points for.
然后你只需传递你想要得到的分数的形状
And that will end up just exploding here into a set of vertices
最终会在这里爆炸成一组顶点
that fill up this love dot graphics dot polygon.
填满了这个爱心的圆点图形圆点多边形
And the end result of that is we get a square.
这样做的最终结果是我们得到了一个平方
And we specifically use polygon instead of love
我们特别使用多边形而不是爱情
dot graphics dot new rectangle because that's what the get
点图形点出新的矩形 因为这就是
world points function explodes out to.
世界积分函数爆炸到
It doesn't explode out to the number of arguments that would satisfy
它不会爆炸到满足以下条件的参数数量
love dot graphics dot rectangle.
喜欢圆点图形 圆点矩形
So not a very exciting example.
所以这不是一个非常令人兴奋的例子
But this is basically the foundation of a full Box2D application.
但这基本上是完整的Box2D应用程序的基础
So any questions as to how this works at all?
那么 对于这是如何运作的 有什么问题吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
观众：是的
I'm wondering.
我在想
How does it determine the center of a abnormal shape?
它如何确定反常形状的中心？
Not like a polygon, square, rectangle, or circle.
不像多边形、正方形、矩形或圆形
COLTON OGDEN: The center of an abnormal shape.
科尔顿·奥格登：反常形状的中心
I'm not entirely sure.
我不完全确定
The circle is just--
这个圈子就是...
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
I'm not entirely sure about a polygon though.
不过 我对多边形不是完全确定
I haven't looked into that into too much detail.
我还没有对此进行太多的细节研究
I can explore that and see.
我可以探索一下 看看
That's something that I think Box2D is--
这就是我认为Box2D是什么--
the actual library implements that and calculates that.
实际的库实现并计算了这一点
Probably based upon calculating the area of--
很可能是根据计算出的--
and to repeat for the camera if I didn't repeat already, it's
如果我还没有重复的话 对着镜头重复 那就是
how does Box2D calculate the center point of something non-symmetrical,
Box2D如何计算非对称物体的中心点
like a polygon?
就像一个多边形？
And best I can understand is that it would do an area calculation off of it
我所能理解的最好的情况是 它会计算出它的面积
and figure out where all the vertices tend towards, I guess.
然后找出所有顶点的走向 我猜
But, yeah, that's something that's implemented in the library.
但是 是的 这是在图书馆中实现的东西
I'm not entirely sure.
我不完全确定
I can look into it and see and then I'll post in the Slack.
我可以查一查 看看 然后我会在《松弛》上发帖
AUDIENCE: It seems like [INAUDIBLE] you did have that,
观众：[INAUDIBLE]看起来你确实有
it would be difficult to place in a very precise spot.
很难把它放在一个非常精确的位置
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
If it were-- yeah.
如果是的话--是的
If we did have an odd shape to get it placed in a exact spot.
如果我们确实有一个奇怪的形状来把它放在一个准确的位置
Yeah, I'm not entirely sure.
是啊 我也不是很确定
I'd have to explore that a little bit.
我得稍微探索一下这一点
Interesting idea though.
不过 这个想法很有趣
But, yeah, that's essentially how we get a Box2D world up and running.
但是 是的 这就是我们建立和运行Box2D世界的基本方式
We have a static body.
我们有一个静止的物体
It's not terribly interesting.
这并不是特别有趣
But with one change--
但有一个变化--
so I have a separate example called dynamic in the source code distro.
所以我在源代码发行版中有一个单独的示例 名为Dynamic
But all we need to do to really see the difference
但我们需要做的就是真正看到不同之处
between a static and dynamic body is on line 48, just change static to dynamic,
静态和动态之间的物体在第48行 只需将静态改为动态
save it, and then rerun it.
保存它 然后重新运行它
And then we'll immediately see that it's affected by gravity
然后我们会立即看到它受到重力的影响
and it moves downwards as we've told the world that our gravity is
它向下移动 正如我们告诉世界 我们的引力是
set to positive 300.
设置为正300
And so that behaves how we would expect it to.
所以这就是我们预期的行为方式
Now, there's nothing else in the scene so it's not particularly interesting.
现在 场景中没有其他东西 所以它不是特别有趣
So I've created a another example called ground.
所以我创建了另一个名为GROUND的例子
So let's go ahead and look at that.
所以让我们继续下去 看看这个
So if we want more interesting behavior, what do we need to do in a nutshell?
因此 如果我们想要更有趣的行为 简而言之 我们需要做什么？
AUDIENCE: Have more shapes and make a ground.
观众：有更多的形状 并形成一个地面
COLTON OGDEN: Some more
科尔顿·奥格登：更多的形状 并形成一个地面
Exactly.
一点儿没错
That's a simple way we can start to get instantly
这是一个简单的方法 我们可以立即开始
a sense of how powerful Box2D is.
了解Box2D的功能有多强大
Just introduce more shapes that interact with each other in different ways.
只需引入更多以不同方式相互作用的形状
So ground is an example that just introduces a ground into our scene,
因此地面是一个例子 它将地面引入到我们的场景中
so that we can see the box fall down and actually collide with something else.
这样我们就能看到盒子掉落下来 实际上撞上了其他东西
And Love2D makes this nice and easy.
而Love2D让这一切变得简单而美好
Excuse me.
打扰一下
They have a actual edge shape that will allow us
它们有一个实际的边缘形状
to basically form where the ground is.
在地面上形成
Anything that collides with this-- it's effectively a line.
任何与之相碰撞的东西 实际上就是一条线
But no matter how fast anything moves in are scene,
但无论场景中的物体移动得有多快
the body will not move past that line.
身体不会越过那条线
So it's a nice, easy way of getting a ground in our scene
所以这是一个很好的 简单的方法来获得一个地面在我们的场景
without having to implement a polygon that maybe has two vertices going
而不必实现可能有两个顶点的多边形
left to right on the screen.
屏幕上从左到右
So that's what we do here.
所以这就是我们在这里做的
We have a ground body, which is a static body, recall.
我们有一个地面身体 这是一个静态的身体 回忆一下
Because the ground shouldn't move.
因为地面不应该移动
We're going to change the box into a dynamic body,
我们要把盒子变成一个动态的物体
but the ground shouldn't move.
但地面不应该移动
The ground should be unaffected by anything.
地面应该不受任何影响
It's going to be static in our scene.
在我们的场景中 它将是静态的
And it's going to have an edge shape.
它会有一个边缘形状
So notice here, we take 0, 0 as the XY.
注意这里 我们取0 0作为XY轴
And then a virtual width is zero.
然后虚拟宽度为零
So with shapes, when we define them here,
所以当我们在这里定义形状时
it's not going to draw the shape at 0, 0, at virtual width in 0.
它不会在0 0 虚拟宽度为0处绘制形状
This is relative to wherever the body is located.
这是相对于身体所在的地方而言的
So wherever our body is, this shape will be
所以无论我们的身体在哪里
drawn with these coordinates, this X and Y and this width and height,
用这些坐标 这个X和Y 这个宽度和高度
relative to that.
相对于此
And specifically, relative to the center point of wherever we place a body.
特别是相对于我们放置物体的中心点
So if this ground is set to 0, 0 at virtual width and zero,
所以如果这个地被设置为0 0在虚拟宽度和零
where do we need to place the actual body for it
我们要把尸体放在哪里
to render the ground appropriately?
来适当地渲染地面
AUDIENCE: The middle bottom.
观众：中间的底部
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah, so we place it towards the middle bottom.
是的 所以我们把它放在中间的底部
So we actually end up placing the body itself here at virtual height minus 30.
所以我们实际上把物体本身放在这里 虚拟高度减30
And when we affix this edge shape to the body, we'll end up,
当我们把这个边缘形状固定在身体上时
even though it says 0, 0 virtual width zero,
即使它写的是0 0虚拟宽度零
it's relative to wherever the body's XY are.
它是相对于物体的XY坐标的
So it's actually going to be 0 virtual height minus 30,
实际上是0虚拟高度减30
virtual width zero will be where that edge exists.
虚拟宽度零将是该边缘存在的地方
And then lastly, just as we did with our box,
最后 就像我们对盒子做的那样
we need a ground fixture so that the ground body knows how
我们需要一个地面固定装置 这样地面机构才能知道如何
it should interact with other things.
它应该与其他东西互动
So we're going to affix the edge shape, which is just a line,
所以我们要贴上边缘形状 这只是一条线
to our ground body.
到我们的地面躯体
And then here we do love dot graphics-- just
然后在这里 我们确实喜欢点图形--只是
as we did with the love dot graphics dot polygon for our box,
就像我们对长方体的Love点图形点多边形所做的那样
we're going to do love dot graphics dot line for our ground body.
我们将为我们的地面实体做点图形点线
And we're going to do the exact same thing, get world points
我们将做同样的事情 获得世界积分
and get points passing the edge shape here.
然后在这里得到通过边缘形状的点数
And I'm also setting a line width of 2 just
我还将线宽设置为2
so we can see it a little bit better.
这样我们就能看得更清楚一点
And I'm going to color it red.
我要把它涂成红色
Again, I colored the box up here green.
再一次 我把盒子涂成了绿色
So go ahead take a look at what this looks like.
所以 继续来看看这是什么样子的
So I'm going to go into ground.
所以我要进入地下了
And so notice-- and I also added a little bit of restitution
所以请注意--我还添加了一点恢复原状
to the-- as I said before, restitution is a quality that a fixture can
对于--就像我之前说的 修复是固定装置可以做到的一种品质
have which gives it bounciness.
具有赋予它弹力的
So rather than just falling flat down onto the ground,
因此 与其只是平直地倒在地上
it bounces a little bit as well.
它也会有一点反弹
And we can see the interaction, so I'll play it one more time.
我们可以看到互动 所以我再播放一次
It starts in the middle.
它从中间开始
And then as soon as it hits the ground body
然后当它一击中地面物体
that we created before, the edge shape, it bounces a couple of times.
我们之前创建的边缘形状 它会反弹几次
But it shows that the box is dynamic, but the ground is static.
但它表明盒子是动态的 但地面是静态的
Nothing influences the position of the ground.
没有任何东西会影响地面的位置
It gets hard set and will stay there permanently.
它变得坚硬 并将永久留在那里
So that shows a nice, easy simple demonstration
这显示了一个很好、简单、简单的演示
of an interaction between a static and a dynamic body.
静态物体和动态物体之间的相互作用
I'm going to go ahead and pull up another example here.
我将继续在这里举另一个例子
So kinematic, recall, what was the difference between a kinematic
所以运动学 回想一下 运动学和
and a static or dynamic body?
是静态的还是动态的呢？
AUDIENCE: Kinematic can move but not influence other shapes.
观众：运动学可以移动 但不能影响其他形状
COLTON OGDEN: Correct.
科尔顿·奥格登：正确
So a kinematic body can move.
所以运动学的物体可以移动
You can ascribe it positional velocity or angular velocity, it's rotation.
你可以把它归结为位置速度或角速度 它是旋转
But when something collides with it, it's not going to be influenced by it.
但当有东西与它相撞时 它不会受到它的影响
It's going to influence the body that it collides with.
它会影响与之相撞的物体
It's going to affect it in some way, but nothing
它会以某种方式影响它 但不会
colliding with the kinematic body is going
与运动学物体的碰撞
to have an effect on its position or its velocity.
对其位置或速度产生影响
It's something that exists and does something programmed
它是某种存在的东西 并做一些编程的事情
and will just do that indefinitely, but it
并将无限期地这样做 但它
will interact with other dynamic bodies as we have programmed.
会按照我们的程序与其他动态体相互作用
And it will not interact with other kinematic bodies either.
它也不会与其他运动学物体相互作用
They will almost pretend that each other doesn't exist.
他们几乎会假装对方并不存在
If you overlap a static and a kinematic body or kinematic and a kinematic body,
如果将静态和运动学实体或运动学和运动学实体重叠
they render on top of each other, but they don't actually
它们在彼此之上渲染 但它们实际上并不
influence each other's position or anything like that.
影响彼此的立场或诸如此类的事情
So I'm going to go ahead and run the kinematic example.
所以我将继续 运行运动学的例子
So here we have a few things going on.
所以这里我们有几件事正在发生
We have the box body that we had before, the dynamic box that
我们有我们以前拥有的盒体 动感盒子
falls from the middle of the screen.
从屏幕中央掉落
We have the ground on the very bottom to catch it.
我们在最底层有一块地可以抓住它
But we have three kinematic boxes in the very center that
但我们在中间有三个运动学盒子
are spinning that influence the green box
正在旋转 影响着绿色盒子
when the green box collides with them.
当绿色的盒子与它们相撞时
So as you can see, it tosses it around and then
如你所见 它把它抛来抛去 然后
the green body falls back to the bottom.
绿色的身体掉落到底部
And in this example I've taken away its restitution.
在这个例子中 我取消了它的原状
So as soon as it hits the ground, it just falls flat.
因此 它一落地 就会平直地坠落
Just like that.
简单得不得了
And so, as you can see, these blue bodies, they're moving.
所以 如你所见 这些蓝色的物体 它们在移动
They have angular velocity indefinitely.
它们有无限的角速度
Specifically 360 degrees per second.
具体来说就是每秒360度
And they will stay in that exact position and rotate in that exact way
它们将保持在正确的位置并以正确的方式旋转
forever.
直到永远
But as soon as they interact with a dynamic body,
但一旦它们与一个有活力的物体互动
they actually cause a collision with that dynamic body.
它们实际上导致了与那个动态物体的碰撞
And the collision resolves and this green body
碰撞解决了 这个绿色的物体
gets tossed around because it's dynamic.
被抛来抛去 因为它是动态的
It will basically do whatever it can to interact with the game world
它基本上会尽其所能与游戏世界互动
as long as it's interacting with other bodies
只要它与其他物体相互作用
and resolving its collision that way.
并以这种方式解决它的碰撞
And so that's the key example between what the three different bodies are
这就是三个不同物体之间的关键例子
fundamentally.
从根本上说
And with these three body types you can construct pretty much any scene
有了这三种体型 你几乎可以构建任何场景
that you want to.
这是你想要的
And obviously the bodies and the fixtures can get insanely complex.
显然 车身和固定装置可能会变得非常复杂
I mean, we can look back here at this first example.
我的意思是 我们可以回顾一下第一个例子
These structures are a composition of many different types of dynamic bodies
这些结构是许多不同类型的动态体的组合
that have been given anchors and joints and all sorts of other things
它们被赋予了锚和关节以及其他各种各样的东西
to make them look as if they're big constructions.
让它们看起来像是大型建筑
But at the end, they're all just a bunch of little bodies
但最后 他们都只是一群小肉体
that are welded together, fixtures that are welded together.
焊接在一起的设备 焊接在一起的设备
And these fundamental building blocks are how you construct scenes like this.
而这些基本的构建块就是如何构建这样的场景的
Put a bunch of these blocks together, weld them together with joints,
把这些块放在一起 用接头把它们焊接在一起
in this case.
在这种情况下
We won't cover joints in the context of this lecture.
我们不会在这堂课的上下文中讨论关节
But if you're wondering how all of these individual things
但如果你想知道所有这些个体的东西
can be collideable while still constructing these massive scenes
是可碰撞的 同时仍然构建这些巨大的场景
and having physics applied to them, they're
将物理学应用于它们 它们是
just jointed together using weld joints or other types of joints, pulley joints
只是使用焊接接头或其他类型的接头、滑轮接头连接在一起
depending on what they are.
这取决于它们是什么
In this case, there is two circle shapes here, circle fixtures,
在这种情况下 这里有两个圆形 圆形灯具
that are the wheels on this cart and then
这是这辆车上的轮子 然后
they're welded to the flat constructions here.
它们被焊接到这里的扁平建筑上
Allowing those to be dynamic allows the wheels to roll, and therefore
允许那些是动态的允许车轮滚动 因此
carry the other load with it.
随身带着另一件重担
Same with this bridge.
这座桥也是如此
I forget the exact name of the joint, but it's a chain of fixtures together
我忘了关节的确切名称 但它是一串固定装置
that are welded by a specific kind of joint.
由特定类型的接头焊接而成
And by putting them together in this way,
通过以这种方式将它们放在一起
you get a bridge and all sorts of things that you could think of,
你有一座桥 还有你能想到的各种东西
including tanks, which is in the notes here.
包括坦克 这是在这里的注释中
This third link, one of them talks about how
第三个环节 其中一个谈到了如何
to implement a tank by having treads going
用踏板来实施坦克
around circles and then a massive body.
绕着圆圈 然后是一个巨大的身体
You could do anything with Box2D, it's an awesome library.
你可以用Box2D做任何事情 它是一个很棒的库
In the context of Angry Birds, really we just
在《愤怒的小鸟》的背景下 我们真的只是
scratched the surface for what is possible here.
对于这里可能发生的事情 触及了皮毛
So I'm going to demo now.
现在我要做演示了
Actually, I enjoyed, I think, this demo, this bit of code,
事实上 我觉得我很喜欢这个演示 这段代码
more than I enjoyed the Angry Birds implementation.
比起我更喜欢《愤怒的小鸟》的实现
And it's a program that I wrote called Ball Pit.
这是我写的一个叫球坑的程序
Oh, by the way, before I get into that.
哦 顺便说一句 在我开始之前
So I'll leave that as a little teaser, I guess.
因此 我想我会把它作为一个小小的预告片
Looking at kinematic, really quickly.
看运动学 真的很快
We're going to look and see that I've created
我们要看看我已经创造了
a table for the kinematic bodies, a table for the fixtures,
运动体工作台 夹具工作台
and then one shape.
然后是一个形状
Because you only need one shape actually,
因为你实际上只需要一个形状
and you can apply one shape to as many bodies
您可以将一个形状应用于任意多个实体
as you want to as long as they all have the same shape.
只要它们都有相同的形状 就可以
I just create three kinematic bodies here.
我在这里只创建了三个运动学实体
So spacing them out relative to the center with this math here.
所以用这个数学方法 把它们相对于中心隔开
They get the string kinematic.
他们得到了运动学的弦
And that's really the key difference.
这真的是关键的区别
And then before finishing, I make sure that I
然后在结束之前 我要确保我
set them to have an angular velocity.
将它们设置为角速度
So this is how you spin something.
所以这就是你旋转东西的方式
If you want to set something to spin indefinitely,
如果你想让某物无限期地旋转
just set an angular velocity.
只要设置一个角速度即可
In this case, 360 times degrees to radians.
在这种情况下 360度为弧度
And that's just a formula written out as a constant, which is just the number--
这只是一个写成常量的公式 这只是一个数字--
I forget offhand what exactly the formula is.
我马上就忘了公式到底是什么
But it's up here.
但它就在上面
It's degrees to radians 0.01745329, et cetera.
温度是弧度0.01745329度 等等
But just like pi, it's a number that you can
但就像圆周率一样 这是一个你可以
use to multiply a number in degrees, and you'll get a number in radians.
用度数乘一个数 就会得到一个弧度数
And there's the reverse up there as well.
而且在那里也有相反的情况
We have to do this because Box2D expects, for any types of rotation,
我们必须这样做 因为Box2D预计 对于任何类型的旋转
it expects it in radians.
它预计会以弧度为单位
I prefer thinking in degrees.
我更喜欢按度思考
So I passed in 360 times degrees to radians.
所以我把360度变成弧度
And so we render down here, just as we did with the box body.
所以我们在这里渲染 就像我们对盒体所做的那样
We render the kinematic bodies, polygon fill, kinematic bodies at i
我们在I处渲染运动体、多边形填充、运动体
get world points kinematic shape get points.
获取世界点运动学形状获取点
Nothing terribly different.
没有太大的不同
The only real key difference is that we've added kinematic as a string
唯一真正的关键区别是我们将运动学添加为字符串
to the constructor for the body.
传递给Body的构造函数
And we've added some angular velocity.
我们增加了一些角速度
And recall, this will make it spin indefinitely,
记住 这会让它无限期地旋转
but it will never be influenced-- its angular velocity will never
但它永远不会受到影响--它的角速度永远不会
be influenced, its position will never be influenced
受到影响 它的地位永远不会受到影响
by anything else in our scene.
在我们的场景中被其他任何东西
So now with that out of the way, I'm going to pull up Ball Pit.
好了 现在我要把球坑拉起来
And maybe I'm just a little bit too excited about this.
也许我只是对这个有点太兴奋了
But I enjoyed this a lot.
但我很享受这个过程
So what it is, is this is like a bigger demonstration
所以 这就像是一个更大的演示
of putting all these pieces together.
把所有这些碎片放在一起
We have a bunch of circle shapes.
我们有一堆圆形的形状
They're all interacting with each other.
它们都在相互作用
They all have physics.
他们都有物理课
And then I have a larger shape here, this square,
然后我这里有一个更大的形状 这个正方形
which has a higher density than everything else.
它的密度比其他任何东西都要高
And by pressing Spacebar I can just dive into--
按下空格键 我就可以直接进入--
throw it into the ball pit, and it'll cause an interaction
把它扔到球坑里 它会引起相互作用
with everything else.
以及其他的一切
And a bug slash feature that I discovered
和我发现的一个错误斜杠功能
about this is that if you press Spacebar over and over again,
如果你一次又一次地按空格键
it never resets its velocity.
它永远不会重置它的速度
So it just slams down into the ball pit.
所以它就撞到了球坑里
So it's just kind of fun, and I think there might actually
所以这只是一种乐趣 我认为实际上
be possibly a game idea in here.
在这里可能是个游戏创意
But, I mean, well, what are the pieces here?
但是 我的意思是 好吧 这里的碎片是什么？
What's different about this?
这有什么不同？
AUDIENCE: They're all dynamic shapes.
观众：它们都是动态的造型
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
So they're all dynamic shapes.
所以它们都是动态的形状
Except for the ground at the very bottom.
除了最底层的地面
And also, hidden from view are actually two more static shapes
此外 隐藏在视野之外的还有另外两个静态形状
on the left and right.
在左边和右边
Because if we didn't have those, all of the balls
因为如果我们没有这些 所有的球
would fall to the side out of view.
会掉到看不见的一边
But yeah, we have the static delimiters for our scene.
但没错 我们的场景有静态分隔符
But we have a bunch of dynamic bodies, the balls are all dynamic.
但我们有一堆动态的物体 这些球都是动态的
And then the square is also dynamic.
然后广场也是充满活力的
And then, like I said before, the only real difference between them
然后 就像我之前说的 他们之间唯一真正的区别是
is that obviously the square is a rectangle.
很明显 正方形是一个长方形
But it also just has a higher density.
但它也有更高的密度
And so by giving it a higher density it pushes everything else-- oh,
因此 通过赋予它更高的密度 它推动了其他一切--哦
what happened there?
那里发生了什么事？
That was weird.
这太奇怪了
It pushes-- I think it went to sleep because we didn't do anything
它在推动--我想它睡着了 因为我们什么都没做
for a while.
一段时间
But it's able to fall through everything else
但它可能会跌落到其他任何地方
because it knows that it's heavier, and that it should push and apply
因为它知道它更重 它应该推动和应用
a larger force to everything else that's around it.
一种更强大的力量来对付它周围的一切
And so by using these fundamental building blocks of what Box2D is,
因此 通过使用Box2D的这些基本构建块
you can construct a lot of really cool simulations and other fun programs
你可以构建很多非常酷的模拟和其他有趣的程序
and actually get interesting game ideas.
真正得到有趣的游戏点子
I'm inclined to believe that Angry Birds started out as somebody messing around
我倾向于相信《愤怒的小鸟》一开始是有人在胡闹
with the Box2D, or physics engine like this.
使用Box2D 或者像这样的物理引擎
And it was inspired by some other game that I should look into a little bit.
它的灵感来自于其他一些游戏 我应该稍微研究一下
But the creators of that game, presumably, found this physics engine
但据推测 这款游戏的创建者发现了这个物理引擎
and were like, oh, this is cool.
然后我们就想 哦 这太酷了
I'm going to put a tower of blocks here and just throw something at it.
我要在这里建一座积木塔 然后向它扔东西
And then they realized, oh, we can make a game out of this.
然后他们意识到 哦 我们可以用这个做一个游戏
And so I encourage you, if you're ever curious to just experiment with things
所以我鼓励你 如果你曾经好奇地尝试一些东西
like that.
就像那样
We could probably turn this into a game.
我们或许可以把这变成一场游戏
I don't know.
我不知道
I like this a lot.
我很喜欢这个
It's a good segue from the abstract, for lack of a better word, examples
这是一个很好的抽象片段 因为没有更好的词、例子
that we used earlier, and merges it more into the realm
并将其更多地合并到领域中
of how can we make something fun with this?
我们如何才能让这件事变得有趣呢？
And so that's how we're going to start moving into the distro today.
这就是我们今天开始进入发行版的方式
So the main topic of today's lecture is Box2D and how we use it to make a game.
所以今天演讲的主要话题是Box2D 以及我们如何使用它来制作游戏
Another thing that we should consider is mouse input.
我们应该考虑的另一件事是鼠标输入
We haven't really used it yet.
我们还没有真正用过它
And I believe I've mentioned it before, slightly offhand.
我想我以前已经提到过了 有点随意
But Love2D makes it super easy.
但Love2D让这一切变得超级简单
It's just like we do with keyboard input.
这就像我们对键盘输入所做的那样
We just have a couple of callbacks that are in main dot Lua,
我们在Main Dot Lua中只有几个回调
mouse pressed and mouse released.
按下鼠标 然后松开鼠标
The difference between these and key pressed and key
这些与按键和按键之间的区别
released is that they also get an X and a Y. Because usually,
他们也会得到一个X和一个Y 因为通常
when you click the mouse or release the mouse,
当您单击鼠标或释放鼠标时
you want to know where it happened because that's
你想知道是在哪里发生的 因为
obviously pertinent to what you're doing when you're using a mouse.
显然与你在使用鼠标时所做的事情有关
So these are fired by Love2D every time you click or release a mouse button.
因此 每当你点击或释放鼠标按键时 Love2D就会触发这些命令
And they get the X the Y and the key, and you
他们得到了X、Y和钥匙 而你
can do whatever you want with those.
你可以用这些东西做任何你想做的事
And just as we've done in prior lectures so
就像我们在之前的课程中所做的那样
that we can use mouse input in other modules besides main dot Lua,
我们可以在主点Lua之外的其他模块中使用鼠标输入
there's a function called love dot mouse dot key pressed and key
有一个功能叫爱点鼠标点按键和按键
released that I implemented in main dot Lua.
发布了我在Main Dot Lua中实现的
You can check those out.
你可以去看看那些
They're very similar to how we did the input tables for the keyboard before.
它们与我们之前制作键盘输入表的方式非常相似
But they allow us to use this functionality inside
但它们允许我们在内部使用此功能
of other functions, other modules, besides main dot Lua.
除了Main Dot Lua之外的其他函数、其他模块
So let's go ahead and start looking at--
所以让我们继续下去 开始看--
this is where we're going to start looking at the distro for Angry Birds
这就是我们开始寻找《愤怒的小鸟》发行版的地方
and how we can take all these pieces and form them into an actual game.
以及我们如何将所有这些棋子组合成一场真正的游戏
So the first thing we'll do, we'll take a look at just a couple of things
所以我们要做的第一件事 我们将只看几件事
and then we'll take a short break and then we'll
然后我们会休息一会儿 然后我们会
get more into the meat of it.
更深入地了解其中的实质
But let me go ahead and clear out all of these.
但让我继续下去 把所有这些都清除掉
And then we're going to pull up-- so the distro is in Angry 50.
然后我们要拉起--所以发行版是愤怒的50
And so main dot Lua is here.
所以Main Dot Lua就在这里
So not a whole lot is different in here.
所以在这里并没有什么不同
So we have two states in our game.
所以我们在游戏中有两种状态
So we had a start and a play state, as we saw before.
所以我们有一个开始和一个比赛状态 就像我们之前看到的
The start state is like we've done before.
开始状态和我们以前做过的一样
The only difference is in this start state, well, for one,
唯一的区别是在这个开始状态下 嗯 首先
it's running a Box2D simulation.
它正在运行Box2D模拟
And two, we're actually using mouse input.
第二 我们实际上使用的是鼠标输入
So actually, let's look at main so you can
所以实际上 让我们看看Main 这样你就可以
see where I've added this, which is different than before.
看看我在哪里添加了这个 这与以前不同
So we have love dot key pressed, as we've seen before.
所以我们按下了Love的点键 就像我们以前看到的那样
But we also have mouse pressed and mouse released.
但我们也有按下鼠标和释放鼠标的方法
And then mouse was pressed and mouse was released.
然后按下鼠标 松开鼠标
So those are the main differences in main dot Lua this time, as opposed
这些是这次Main Dot Lua的主要不同之处 而不是
to last prior lectures, which we only had keyboard input.
上一节课 我们只用键盘输入
And as you can see here, we have input tables for keys pressed and released
正如您在这里看到的 我们有按下和释放键的输入表
on the mouse.
在鼠标上
And so we initialized those to empty on every update frame
因此 我们将其初始化为在每个更新帧上清空
just like we've done with the keyboard.
就像我们对键盘所做的那样
And then the input tables get updated in the callback functions
然后在回调函数中更新输入表
as we've done before.
就像我们以前做过的那样
And so that's basically all that's different about main dot Lua this time.
这就是这次Main Dot Lua的所有不同之处
And that's how we've tied together the new mouse functions that we've just
这就是我们将刚刚推出的新鼠标功能捆绑在一起的方式
looked at into our game.
看着我们的比赛
The states that exist in our game are play state and start state.
我们的游戏中存在的状态是PLAY状态和START状态
So very simple.
非常简单
Very similar to last week where we looked at Zelda,
非常类似于上周我们观看塞尔达的比赛
we only basically had a start state and a play state.
我们基本上只有一个开始状态和一个比赛状态
The start state, we can see here, just to tie together
开始状态 我们可以在这里看到 只是为了连接在一起
the last bit of our usage of the mouse.
鼠标的最后一点用法
Love dot mouse dot was pressed 1.
爱点鼠标点被按下1点
Does anybody know what this 1 is?
有人知道这个1是什么吗？
AUDIENCE: Is that left click?
观众：那是左键点击吗？
COLTON OGDEN: It is left click.
科尔顿·奥格登：点击鼠标左键
So Love2D assigns integer values to all of your mouse buttons.
因此 Love2D会将整数值指定给所有鼠标按键
And 1 is traditionally the default value for left click.
而1传统上是左击的缺省值
Some frameworks will use 0.
一些框架将使用0
But Lua, 1 index so start with 1 instead of 0.
但是Lua 1索引是从1开始的 而不是0
The thing about the start state here that's kind of cool and interesting.
关于这里的开始状态 这是一种酷和有趣的事情
So I'm going to go ahead and play it again, the game.
所以我要继续下去 再玩一次 这个游戏
So we start off and right off the gate, just to make things interesting
所以我们一开始就开始 只是为了让事情变得有趣
rather than just have a static screen that says
而不是只有一个静态屏幕 上面显示
Anger 50 click to start, we're actually running a Love2D,
愤怒50点击开始 我们实际上正在运行一个Love2D
a Box2D simulation here.
在这里进行Box2D模拟
It's a world with a bunch of squares.
这是一个有一堆方块的世界
And so what kind of bodies are all of these?
那么 这些都是什么样的身体呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: They're all dynamic bodies.
科尔顿·奥格登：它们都是有活力的物体
And we've encapsulated them all, just as we did before in the ball pit example,
我们已经将它们全部封装起来 就像我们之前在球坑例子中所做的那样
with some invisible static bodies on the left, right, and bottom of the screen.
屏幕的左侧、右侧和底部都有一些看不见的静态体
Because if we didn't have those static bodies
因为如果我们没有那些静止的物体
they would just fall all the way down.
它们只会一路往下掉
And the nice thing is we don't actually have to render anything.
最好的是 我们实际上不需要渲染任何东西
So if you want maybe an invisible barrier for something in your game,
所以如果你想在你的游戏中为某些东西设置一个无形的障碍
or you want to encapsulate something, something physical,
或者你想要封装一些东西 一些物质上的东西
you don't have to render anything.
您不必渲染任何内容
You can just have arbitrarily shaped and positioned static bodies.
你可以只拥有任意形状和位置的静态物体
And that will act as a container.
而这将充当一个容器
So that's all we're doing there.
这就是我们在那里所做的一切
We have a container set for all of our little square alien guys.
我们为我们所有的小正方形外星人准备了一个集装箱
And by creating, I think, a hundred of them and just letting them drop,
我认为 通过创造100个这样的物体 然后让它们掉落
we have this interesting visual start to our game
我们的游戏有一个有趣的视觉开始
with very, very minimal effort.
只需非常非常小的努力
So we can take a look at this.
让我们来看看这个
So in our start state init, as I said before, we have a world.
所以在我们的开始状态init中 正如我之前所说的 我们有一个世界
We obviously need a member of new world.
我们显然需要一个新世界的成员
Anytime we do any Box2D stuff you have to start
任何时候我们做任何Box2D的事情你都必须开始
by having a love dot physics dot new world,
通过让爱点缀新世界 物理点点新世界
else you won't be able to run any simulations.
否则 您将无法运行任何模拟
Going to create a ground, walls, and then a bunch of aliens.
建造一片地面 一堵墙 然后是一群外星人
So this here, we can see that we have a table that we're inserting aliens into.
所以在这里 我们可以看到我们有一个表格 我们正在向其中插入外星人
But we have a class called alien.
但我们有一个班级叫外星人
So anybody want to ballpark what an alien class ultimately
所以 有没有人想大致了解一下外星人的职业
encapsulates or ultimately is?
封装了还是最终是？
AUDIENCE: Probably the way it looks, like the skin.
观众：可能是它的外观 就像皮肤一样
COLTON OGDEN: It is, yeah, that's definitely a part of it.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的 这绝对是其中的一部分
So the way it looks, or it's skin.
所以它看起来 或者是它的皮肤
So it does have a reference to that.
所以它确实提到了这一点
And then more functionally, it also possesses a body and a fixture.
然后更多的功能 它还拥有一个身体和一个固定装置
So rather than having a bunch of bodies and fixtures
因此 与其让一堆身体和固定装置
that are separated out and maybe just in tables
它们是分开的 可能只在桌子上
at the surface level of whatever, our level, just wrap them in a class.
在任何东西的表面水平上 我们的水平 只需将它们包装在一个类中
And then we just can maintain a reference
然后我们就可以保持一个引用
to each individual alien's body and fixture that way.
每一个外星人的身体和固定装置
So it's a little bit more encapsulated.
所以它更具封装性
It's a little bit more object oriented, little bit cleaner in my opinion.
在我看来 它更面向对象 更简洁
The alien class can take square or round as its--
外星人阶级可以用正方形或圆形作为它的--
well, it can take anything you want to as its type.
嗯 它可以接受任何你想要的类型
So this will ultimately decide how it's rendered and what shape it gets.
因此 这最终将决定它是如何渲染的 以及它的形状
But if it's square, which is the default, so if you just
但如果它是方形的 这是默认的 所以如果你只是
create an alien with no type, it will get
创造一个没有类型的外星人 它会得到
a love dot physics dot rectangle shape.
一个爱心网点 物理网点呈长方形
So as we saw before, that's just a box.
所以 正如我们之前看到的 这只是一个盒子
And then if not, we just default to circle shape.
如果不是 我们就默认为圆形
But you could program it to take in whatever shape you want,
但你可以把它编程成你想要的任何形状
and then just give it that shape.
然后就给它那个形状
And you don't really have to do much in terms
你真的不需要做太多的事情
of coding how it interacts with anything else in terms of collision, at least.
编码它如何与其他任何东西相互作用 至少在碰撞方面是这样
Because, thankfully, Box2D will know, OK, it's a circle.
因为 谢天谢地 Box2D会知道 好的 这是一个圆
It should spin around and interact with things like a circle.
它应该旋转 并与像圆圈一样的东西互动
Or it's a rectangle so it should interact with things like it's a box.
或者它是一个矩形 所以它应该与像盒子一样的东西交互
Just nice and convenient.
只是又好又方便
And then we'll just create a fixture here.
然后我们将在这里创建一个固定装置
This set user data function here is important
此处的设置用户数据功能很重要
because we'll see in the context of how we actually resolve collisions
因为我们将在我们如何实际解决碰撞的上下文中看到
in a customized way, we'll need user data
以定制的方式 我们需要用户数据
to be able to differentiate what gets collided in our world.
能够区分出在我们的世界中发生碰撞的东西
But at the moment you can just know that this basically allows us to pass in--
但目前你可以知道 这基本上允许我们进入--
to set arbitrary data onto a fixture.
将任意数据设置到灯具上
So we can say, fixture set user data alien, the string alien.
所以我们可以说 灯具集用户数据外星人 串外星人
And what that means is that fixture has some customized metadata about it that
这意味着Fixture有一些关于它的定制元数据
says, this is an alien.
说 这是一个外星人
It's whatever we want to do with it.
这是我们想要用它做的任何事情
We could give this a table as well.
我们也可以给这张桌子
We could just say, the user data is a table
我们可以这样说 用户数据是一个表
and then has a bunch of information that we can then use at collision time
然后有一堆信息 我们可以在碰撞时使用
to perform different work on it.
对它进行不同的工作
But this set user data function is how we
但是这个设置用户数据的功能是我们如何
are able to resolve collisions between obstacles and aliens differently than,
能够以不同的方式解决障碍和外星人之间的碰撞
say players and aliens, or even the alien and the ground.
比如玩家和外星人 甚至外星人和地面
Because when we do any Box2D collision, right, the world's
因为当我们做任何Box2D碰撞时 对 世界
taking care of the collisions for us.
为我们解决碰撞问题
How do we tell the world, OK, when I hit the ground I want to play a sound,
我们如何告诉世界 好吧 当我落地时 我想要播放一个声音
but not do anything.
但什么都不做
If I hit this box at this velocity, I want it to destroy it.
如果我以这个速度撞击这个盒子 我想让它摧毁它
If I hit the alien, I want the alien to disappear
如果我击中外星人 我希望外星人消失
and I want to show a victory label.
我想展示一个胜利的标签
How do we do all these different things?
我们如何做所有这些不同的事情？
We do that with what are called collision callbacks
我们通过所谓的冲突回调来做到这一点
in the context of Box2D.
在Box2D的上下文中
And we'll see how that works.
我们将拭目以待
But suffice to say, user data will be very important coming forward.
但可以说 用户数据将是非常重要的
And then this launched false, actually we don't end up
然后这个推出了假的 实际上我们并没有结束
using this so this is irrelevant.
使用这个 所以这是无关紧要的
But it has a render function here, which just takes in the bodies X and Y
但它在这里有一个渲染函数 它只接受身体X和Y
and will draw it at the angle that it's at.
并会以它所在的角度绘制它
So that's an important thing.
所以这是一件重要的事情
When we before, what we were doing is drawing things via shapes.
以前 我们所做的是通过形状来画东西
So love dot graphics dot polygon, love dot graphics dot circle,
所以爱点图形的点多边形 爱点图形的点圆
love dot graphics dot line.
喜欢网点图形的网点线
But if we want to draw a sprite instead, we
但如果我们想要画一个精灵 我们
need to draw it at the right position, first of all, right?
首先需要把它画在正确的位置 对吗？
And then things also rotate in Box2D.
然后物体也会在Box2D中旋转
So we need to draw it at the right angle.
所以我们需要把它画在正确的角度
So what we do is we can actually query the body for its X.
所以我们要做的是 我们可以在身体上查询它的X
We can query the body for its Y. And we can also query the body for its angle.
我们可以查询物体的Y 也可以查询物体的角度
And then we can draw the texture and the quad
然后我们可以绘制纹理和四边形
that we want to using those XY and the angle,
我们想要利用XY和角度
and that will have the effect of drawing a sprite in the world that
这将产生在世界上画出一个精灵的效果
mirrors what's going on in Box2D, rather than just a simple shape.
反映了Box2D中正在发生的事情 而不仅仅是一个简单的形状
So that's as simple as it is for drawing a sprite instead of a shape.
所以这就像画一个精灵而不是一个形状一样简单
You can see here, the 17.5 17.5.
你可以在这里看到 17.5号高速公路
Does anybody know what that's for?
有人知道这是干嘛用的吗？
AUDIENCE: Not sure.
观众：不确定
COLTON OGDEN: So 17.5 17.5 at the end is half of the width
科尔顿·奥格登：所以17.5、17.5、17.5是宽度的一半
and half of the height of the aliens.
外星人身高的一半
So aliens are 35 by 35 in this game.
所以外星人在这个游戏中是35乘35的
We pass those in.
我们把这些都传进去
This is the center of origin.
这是起源的中心
So when we rotate something by center of origin,
所以当我们以原点为中心旋转物体时
it basically describes where the rotation is going to take place.
它基本上描述了旋转将在哪里发生
So if it's rotated about the top left and we rotate something,
所以如果它绕着左上角旋转 我们旋转一些东西
it's going to have the effect of the sprite going around
它会产生像精灵一样的效果
in a circle in sort of an odd way.
以一种奇怪的方式围成一圈
If we rotate the sprite based on the center of origin of the actual sprite
如果我们基于实际精灵的原点旋转精灵
itself, that will have the effect of rotating the sprite on its center.
本身 这将具有在其中心旋转精灵的效果
So you can set that origin wherever you want to
因此 您可以将原点设置为您想要设置位置
and it'll perform a 360 degree rotation about that point.
它将围绕该点进行360度旋转
And we're setting that point to half--
我们将这一点设定为一半--
to basically the middle of where we're drawing the sprite.
基本上到我们画精灵的中间
So that will have the effect of when we give it this angle here,
所以当我们给它这个角度时 它会产生这样的效果
self dot body to get angle, the rotation will take place in place.
自身网体要获得角度 旋转时就会发生在原地
It won't take place-- it won't be some sort of weird about the top left corner
这不会发生--左上角不会有什么奇怪的事情
rotation, which is not what we want.
轮换 这不是我们想要的
So when you see center of origin being modified like that,
因此 当你看到起源中心被这样修改时
you can assume that it's because we have an offset
你可以假设这是因为我们有一个偏移量
and we're trying to find the center of where we're drawing
我们试图找到我们所画的地方的中心
and rotate about that to do an in place rotation.
然后绕着它旋转 做一个原地旋转
But not necessarily, you could also draw something.
但不一定 你也可以画一些东西
You could also, maybe you want something some sort of magical ball of energy
你也可以 也许你想要某种神奇的能量球
to rotate about a rod or something.
绕着棍子或其他东西旋转
And so you want it to rotate around a different center,
所以你想让它绕着不同的中心旋转
or whatever you want arbitrarily.
或者你随意想要的任何东西
But typically, at least mostly that I've seen,
但通常情况下 至少在我见过的大部分情况下
this is useful for making sure that your rotations, your in place rotations,
这对于确保您的旋转 您的原地旋转
are accurately rendered.
被准确地渲染
So any questions about how the alien class works?
关于外星人职业是如何工作的 有什么问题吗？
All right.
好的
So that's the alien class.
这就是外星人班级
That's the basically the fundamental building block of our game.
这基本上是我们游戏的基本组成部分
The other part is the obstacle.
另一个部分是障碍
We have obstacles and we have aliens.
我们有障碍 我们有外星人
The obstacles and aliens are actually very similar.
障碍物和外星人实际上非常相似
So what's the difference between--
那么 这两者有什么不同呢？
I mean, ultimately, how are they similar?
我的意思是 归根结底 它们有什么相似之处？
AUDIENCE: They're both dynamic [INAUDIBLE]..
观众：他们都很有活力
COLTON OGDEN: They're both dynamic bodies, yeah.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的 它们都是充满活力的物体
Really, the only thing that's different about a obstacle and an alien
真的 障碍物和外星人唯一不同的是
is what we do with them in our scene and how they're rendered.
是我们在场景中如何处理它们以及它们是如何渲染的
But they function very similarly.
但它们的功能非常相似
They're just dynamic bodies that we give a shape to
它们只是我们赋予其形状的动态体
and we render them with that shape.
我们把它们渲染成那个形状
In this case, the obstacle constructor, we've
在这种情况下 障碍构造器 我们已经
decided to design it such that it could take a shape horizontal or vertical,
我决定把它设计成水平或垂直的形状
which is similar to the type that we saw before with the alien,
这与我们之前看到的外星人的类型相似
where it could be square or circular.
它可以是正方形也可以是圆形
In this case, if we look back at our sprite sheet back here,
在这种情况下 如果我们回过头来看看我们的精灵工作表
we can see there's a ton of different shapes.
我们可以看到有一大堆不同的形状
But the only two shapes that we're going to use in the context of this game,
但我们在这个游戏中要用到的只有两个形状
just for this demonstration, are the horizontal, clean wooden shape here
仅为演示 这里是水平的、干净的木制形状
and the vertical one that's right here.
还有这个垂直的 就在这里
And so in order to find those out I had to open up
所以为了找出这些东西 我不得不敞开心扉
basically this sprite in my sprite editor,
基本上就是我的精灵编辑器中的这个精灵
figure out where the XY width and height were, and then create
找出XY宽度和高度的位置 然后创建
a quad manually off of that.
一个四人手动队离开那里
And then I edited the util dot Lua-- or not util dot Lua,
然后我编辑了util点Lua--或者不是util点Lua
the dependencies dot Lua here.
依赖关系在这里点缀着Lua
Normally we just create gframes and then we use generate quads.
正常情况下 我们只需创建框架 然后使用生成四边形
And you can do that like with the aliens and with the tiles, the tiles
你可以像对待外星人一样 用瓷砖 瓷砖
being this sprite sheet that--
就是这张精灵床单--
this one right here.
这个就在这里
These are 35 by 35.
这些是35乘35的
These are not 35 by 35.
这些不是35x35
These are a bunch of different shapes and sizes.
这些是一堆不同形状和大小的东西
So I went through and gframes wood is for manually created quads here.
所以我检查了一下 格框木板是用来手工制作四边形的
And then there's four because I also added the semi broken shapes as well.
然后是四个 因为我还添加了半断线的形状
But we don't actually use those.
但我们实际上并不使用这些
But you could decide to turn these into these on collision,
但你可以决定在碰撞时把这些变成这些
perhaps maybe if the velocity isn't strong enough to break it necessarily,
也许如果速度还不够强 不足以打破它
but you want to have some sort of feedback that you collided with it.
但你想要得到某种反馈 说你与它发生了冲突
You can just set maybe the frame to 1 or 2 on collision for that object,
您只需将该对象的碰撞帧设置为1或2即可
instead of 2 and render it appropriately.
而不是2 并适当地渲染它
But if you're dealing with a sprite sheet
但如果你面对的是精灵床单
and that sprite sheet has odd distribution of its sprites,
而那张精灵纸上的精灵分布得很奇怪
sometimes you have to figure out where the offsets are manually
有时 您必须手动找出偏移量的位置
and do it that way.
然后用这种方式来做
The ideal is that you don't have to and that you can do it programmatically.
理想的情况是 您不必这样做 并且可以通过编程来完成
But it really depends on the game, what your domain is
但这真的取决于游戏 你的域名是什么
and what objects you're interacting with in the scene.
以及您在场景中与哪些对象交互
Any questions on the why or how as to that?
对于为什么或如何做到这一点 有什么问题吗？
Cool.
凉爽的
So back to the obstacle.
那么回到障碍上来吧
So they're horizontal or vertical, and what that does
所以它们是水平的或垂直的 这是
is it sets the frame to 2 or 4.
是将帧设置为2还是4
And the 2 or 4 being in gframes that would, the 4 quads that I had a hand,
两个或四个在框架中 我有一只手的四个四边形
figure out the coordinates for.
计算出的坐标
And really, it's not a whole lot different at that point.
真的 在这一点上并没有太大的不同
If it's a horizontal or a vertical shape,
如果它是水平或垂直的形状
then we need to set its width and height appropriately.
然后我们需要适当地设置它的宽度和高度
Because it's going to have a different width and a different height.
因为它会有不同的宽度和高度
If it's vertical, obviously the height is higher than the width.
如果它是垂直的 显然高度高于宽度
And if it's horizontal, the opposite is true.
如果它是水平的 情况正好相反
But they're both a rectangle shape.
但它们都是长方形的
So you can pass in the width and the height
这样你就可以传递宽度和高度
after you calculate that, and give it the right shape,
在你计算之后 并给它正确的形状
and then ascribe it a fixture.
然后将其归因于一种固定装置
And then set user data in this case, we set user data to obstacle.
然后设置用户数据在这种情况下 我们将用户数据设置为障碍
So now that obstacle, the fixture specifically,
所以现在这个障碍 特别是固定装置
knows that it's an obstacle, as opposed to being an alien, as opposed
知道这是一种障碍 而不是作为一个外星人 而不是
to being anything else, as opposed to being the ground.
成为其他任何东西 而不是成为地面
And so when we explore in a few minutes what the custom collision, world
因此 当我们在几分钟内探索什么定制碰撞 世界
collision callbacks, that we can actually
碰撞回调 我们实际上可以
define all this interesting collision behavior for,
定义所有这些有趣的碰撞行为
this user data is going to be relevant.
这些用户数据将是相关的
And then we render it just like we render the alien as before.
然后我们像以前一样渲染外星人一样渲染它
So any questions on obstacles and aliens, how they differ,
所以任何关于障碍物和外星人的问题 它们有什么不同
how they're the same?
它们有什么相同之处？
Cool.
凉爽的
All right.
好的
Let's take a five minute now.
现在让我们休息五分钟
When we get back, we're going to actually look at the play state.
当我们回来时 我们将实际查看播放状态
We're going to look at what makes a level.
我们来看看怎样才能达到水平
And we're going to actually look at how we can customize the world
我们将真正了解如何定制这个世界
to resolve collisions in ways that are relevant to our game behavior.
以与我们的游戏行为相关的方式解决冲突
As in, how to make things break when we collide with them,
比如 当我们与物体相撞时 如何让它们破碎
how to make the victory screen pop up when we've destroyed the bird,
当我们摧毁这只鸟时 如何让胜利屏幕弹出来
so on and so forth.
以此类推
All right.
好的
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
So before we took a break, we were talking
所以在我们休息之前 我们在谈论
about the aliens and obstacles that are in our game
关于我们游戏中的外星人和障碍
world that interact with each other.
相互影响的世界
They are the backbone of what makes our games slash Angry Birds work.
他们是让我们的游戏大幅削减《愤怒的小鸟》发挥作用的支柱
You throw aliens into the obstacles, obstacles break,
你把外星人扔进障碍物 障碍物就会被打破
the bad pigs slash aliens die and then you score points.
坏猪砍死外星人 然后你就得分了
But we actually have to model these interactions
但我们实际上必须对这些相互作用进行建模
and we have to tell our game, our world, what
我们必须告诉我们的游戏 我们的世界 什么
to do when these collisions happen in order for things more interesting
当这些碰撞发生时 为了让事情变得更有趣
than just things bouncing off each other to work.
而不仅仅是物体相互弹跳才能工作
That's the default behavior.
这是默认行为
Box2D's goal, by default, is when two things overlap,
默认情况下 Box2D的目标是当两个物体重叠时
assuming that they're dynamic or at least one of them is dynamic,
假设它们是动态的 或者至少其中一个是动态的
is to push the dynamic bodies away until they no longer overlap
就是推开动态物体 直到它们不再重叠
via either position or rotation.
通过位置或旋转
But that's not the gist or the goal of our game.
但这不是我们比赛的主旨或目标
Because what we want to have happen is different things happen
因为我们希望发生的是不同的事情发生
and certain things to disappear and to break and all sorts of other things
某些东西消失了 破碎了 还有各种各样的其他东西
to happen when different kinds of objects
当不同种类的物体
interact with different kinds of objects at differing speeds.
以不同的速度与不同类型的物体交互
So in order to do this, we need to define collision callbacks
因此 为了做到这一点 我们需要定义冲突回调
for our world.
为了我们的世界
So a callback, recall, is a function that gets
因此 回调 recall 是一个函数 它得到
called back when something happens.
出事的时候给我回电话
It's just something that will get called at a specific time or later on.
它只是在特定时间或以后会被调用的东西
And we can define these callbacks for our world
我们可以为我们的世界定义这些回调
such that when two things collide with each other,
这样当两个物体相互碰撞时
it will execute this call back and then perform the corresponding logic
它将执行此回调 然后执行相应的逻辑
that we've defined therein.
这是我们在其中定义的
And with every collision in Box2D, there are four callbacks that take place.
对于Box2D中的每个冲突 都会发生四个回调
There's begin contact, so when two things begin to overlap
有开始接触 所以当两件事开始重叠时
or begin to contact one another.
或者开始彼此联系
End contact, so once that ends, once two objects
结束接触 所以一旦结束 一旦两个物体
are pushed away from each other.
被彼此推开
Presolved, which happens right before the collision actually gets
已预先解决 这发生在碰撞实际得到
solved in Box2D, meaning that the things get pushed away from each other.
在Box2D中解决 这意味着这些东西相互推开
And then postsolved, meaning right after they get pushed away from each other.
然后后解决 意思是在他们被推开之后
And the postsolved in particular is interesting
尤其是后解题很有趣
because it gets the information about how the collision needed to resolve.
因为它获得了有关如何解决冲突的信息
So how much velocity or rotation needed to happen within that interaction.
那么在这种相互作用中需要多大的速度或自转
And we will not be using end contact, presolve, or postsolve.
我们不会使用末端接触、预解算或后解算
We will only be using begin contact because, really, that's
我们将只使用Begin Contact 因为 真的
all we need in order to model the behavior that we're looking for.
我们所需要的就是模拟我们正在寻找的行为
Because anything that happens in our game
因为在我们的游戏中发生的任何事情
we can just figure it out as soon as two objects touch each other.
只要两个物体相互接触 我们就能搞清楚
And these are things, if you're interested in a tutorial that
这些都是 如果你对一个教程感兴趣的话
goes over these in perhaps a little bit more detail,
可能会更详细地介绍这些内容
there's a link here in the slides.
幻灯片中有一个链接
But I'll show you how to actually implement these callbacks yourself.
但我将向您展示如何自己实际实现这些回调
You do this via a function called world set callbacks,
这是通过一个名为World Set Callback的函数来实现的
in this case, F1, F2, F3, F4.
在本例中为F1、F2、F3、F4
And recall, because Lua is a dynamic language where functions
回想一下 因为Lua是一种动态语言 其中函数
are first class objects, you can pass in functions as arguments
是第一类对象 则可以将函数作为参数传递
to other functions.
转到其他功能
And that's what we're doing here.
这就是我们在这里做的事情
So this is assuming that we have four functions
假设我们有四个函数
we've defined called begin contact, end contact. presolve, or postsolve.
我们已经定义了开始接触 结束接触 解算前或解算后
Their actual names don't matter at all.
他们的真实名字根本无关紧要
These are just the de facto names for them.
这些只是它们的实际名称
What matters is that you have the logic there and you pass in function objects
重要的是 您在那里有逻辑 并且您传递函数对象
that perform something.
它们会表现出一些东西
And you can pass in all empty functions and Box2D will still behave as normal.
并且您可以传入所有空函数 而Box2D仍将正常运行
These are only for when you want more complicated behavior out of your game
只有当你想要更复杂的行为从你的游戏中消失的时候 这些才会出现
than just things bouncing off of each other
不只是物体相互弹跳
and moving relative to one another.
并且彼此相对移动
So does that make sense?
那么 这有意义吗？
So we'll see how this actually works.
因此 我们将看看这是如何实际工作的
We're going to go ahead and open up level dot Lua.
我们将继续进行 并开放Level doLua
So level dot Lua is a container class that
因此Level..Lua是一个容器类
basically has our game level in it, including
基本上有我们的游戏水平 包括
the world and all the entities.
世界和所有实体
And we update it and are able to model, effectively,
我们更新它 并能够有效地建模
like a level from Angry Birds.
就像《愤怒的小鸟》中的关卡
That's really what it is.
事实就是如此
It has a world.
它有一个世界
So the level has its own world with 300 positive Y gravity, as we saw before.
所以水平线有自己的世界 有300正Y重力 就像我们之前看到的
It has a table called destroyed bodies.
它有一张桌子 叫做被毁的身体
And we'll see that in a second.
我们稍后会看到这一点
And then here we have four functions.
然后这里我们有四个函数
Starting on line 22, we have begin contact, which is a long function.
从第22行开始 我们有了Begin Contact 这是一个长函数
And then we have end contact, presolve, and postsolve.
然后我们有结束接触 预解和后解
Those are the four callback functions that I
这四个回调函数是我
alluded to just a few seconds ago.
几秒钟前才提到
They take in slightly different signatures.
他们接受的签名略有不同
The first three take A, B, and collision.
前三个分别是A、B和碰撞
And then the last one takes in A, B, collision, and then a normal impulse
然后最后一个是A B 碰撞 然后是正常的冲量
and a tangent impulse, which are the forces that it needed to apply in order
和切线冲量 这是它需要按顺序施加的力
to push apart the two objects.
将这两个物体分开
Like I said, we won't be using these three functions.
就像我说的 我们不会使用这三个函数
But there might be a situation where you need to use those functions.
但在某些情况下 您可能需要使用这些函数
Maybe you want end contact because, in your game, two objects attached
也许你想要结束接触 因为在你的游戏中 两个物体连接在一起
to one another, when they collide maybe they're magnetic or something,
当它们相互碰撞时 也许它们是有磁性的或什么的
and then once they pull apart maybe you want a particle effect
然后 一旦它们分开 也许你想要粒子效果
or something to show that they've separated or something.
或者是什么来表明他们已经分居了什么的
And then presolve and postsolve.
然后进行预解算和后解算
Presolve, offhand I can't think of a use case,
PResolve 我现在想不出一个用例
but postsolve could be useful for, depending on your game,
但后期解算可能有用 取决于您的游戏
whether you need to just figure out maybe the amount of force
你是不是只需要计算出
that they needed to separate.
他们需要分开
Maybe you multiply that by some amount and cause some sort of dramatic effect.
也许你把它乘以某个数量 就会产生某种戏剧性的效果
Those are ultimately dependent on the domain of your game.
这些最终取决于您的游戏领域
The important function that we'll be using today
我们今天要使用的重要功能
is the first one, begin contact.
是第一个 开始联系
And notice, that we've defined these four functions,
注意 我们已经定义了这四个函数
even if these three are just empty.
即使这三个只是空的
But we pass in, as I said before, the set callbacks
但就像我之前说过的那样 我们通过了SET回调
function takes in those four functions.
函数包含这四个函数
And notice another interesting thing, because of Lua's dynamic nature, line
注意另一件有趣的事情 因为Lua的动态性质 Line
11 you can see that we have level init, which
11您可以看到我们有Level init 它
is the constructor for our level class.
是我们的Level类的构造函数
Within the constructor we are defining more functions.
在构造函数中 我们定义了更多函数
You can define functions as many layers deep as you want to.
您可以根据需要定义任意多层的函数
And you can even return functions from functions, which
您甚至可以从函数返回函数 这
are called higher order functions.
被称为高阶函数
Really do whatever you want to.
真的想做什么就做什么
In this case we're just defining the collision callbacks here inside
在本例中 我们只是在内部定义冲突回调
of our init.
我们的初始版本
But you could put the most anywhere you want to.
但你可以把最多的放在你想放的任何地方
You can have them outside of the class, you can have them wherever you want.
你可以在课外使用 你可以在任何你想要的地方使用
You can have them be global functions in your main dot Lua,
您可以在您的主点Lua中将它们作为全局函数
which I don't know how I feel about that.
我不知道我对此有何感想
But you can do whatever you want to as long as the functions exist
但只要这些功能存在 您就可以做任何您想做的事情
and you can reference their symbols, you can pass them
你可以引用他们的符号 你可以传递他们
into self dot world set callbacks.
进入自己的点世界 设置回调
And now, whenever a collision happens in the world period,
现在 每当碰撞发生在世界周期
it's going to call all four of those functions
它会调用这四个函数
at each stage of each collision.
在每次碰撞的每个阶段
So you could see that potentially getting a little bit
所以你可以看到
hairy if you were to scale high enough with all of your logic.
如果你用你所有的逻辑来衡量的话
If you had a million lines of code in each of these
如果你有一百万行代码在每一个
and its executing million lines of code per collision,
每次碰撞它要执行百万行代码
you could run into trouble.
你可能会遇到麻烦
But, fortunately, we're not going anywhere near that.
但幸运的是 我们不会去接近它
The gist of begin contact, so it takes in an A and a B and a collision.
开始接触的要点 所以它接受了A B和碰撞
We don't end up using the collision itself, we just use the A and the B
我们不用碰撞本身 我们只用A和B
because that's all we need for our game world.
因为这就是我们游戏世界所需要的
The A and the B are what?
A和B是什么？
Do we know what the A and the B are?
我们知道A和B是什么吗？
AUDIENCE: Probably the two objects [INAUDIBLE]..
观众：可能是两个物体[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: The two objects.
科尔顿·奥格登：这两个物体
Do you know whether it's a body or a fixture?
你知道是尸体还是固定物吗？
AUDIENCE: It would the fixture.
观众：这将是固定装置
COLTON OGDEN: It would be the fixture.
科尔顿·奥格登：这将是一个固定装置
The fixtures collide with each other, not the bodies.
是固定装置相互碰撞 而不是身体
So when you have a body, recall that the fixture attaches the shape to a body.
所以当你有一个实体时 回忆一下夹具将形状附加到实体上
The body is just a position and velocity container for a bunch of fixtures,
物体只是一个位置和速度的容器
the body is.
身体是
Each individual fixture collides with other things,
每一个固定装置都会与其他东西发生碰撞
other fixtures in your game world.
你游戏世界里的其他装置
And so, recall that before we had fixture
所以 回想一下 在我们有固定装置之前
set user data because that's what we ended up
设置用户数据 因为这就是我们最终
needing to have data on when we do the collisions.
我们需要有碰撞的数据
We check to see via get user data what something is
我们通过获取用户数据来检查
or what metadata we've given to that fixture.
或者我们给那个装置的元数据
And then we can then separate different classes of objects this way.
然后我们就可以用这种方法来区分不同类别的对象
We can say, oh, this object was an alien, or this object was an obstacle,
我们可以说 哦 这个物体是外星人 或者这个物体是一个障碍物
or this object was the ground.
或者这个物体是地面
And then we can say, oh, did we collide with an alien?
然后我们可以说 哦 我们是不是撞上了外星人？
Was the collision between an alien and the ground?
是外星人与地面的碰撞？
If it was, OK, let's play a bounce sound effect.
如果是的话 好吧 让我们播放一个弹跳的声音效果
And if it was between an alien and the other alien, the player
如果是一个外星人和另一个外星人
and the other alien, and the velocity was fast enough,
和另一个外星人 而且速度足够快
OK, the alien should die.
好吧 外星人应该去死
Right?
对吗？
We can do arbitrary things.
我们可以做武断的事情
And so the way that I've programmed it here such that we
所以我在这里编程的方式是 我们
can see what two things interacted with each other,
可以看到是什么两个东西相互作用
and this is a very simple use of user data.
这是对用户数据的一个非常简单的使用
All we we're doing in this code base is just assigning strings to fixtures,
我们在这个代码库中所做的只是将字符串分配给装备
but you could assign tables to fixtures with arbitrary amounts of data
但是您可以将表分配给具有任意数据量的装置
and do all sorts of things.
做各种各样的事情
In this case, we're only using strings.
在本例中 我们只使用字符串
So I create a table, an empty table, and then I just
所以我创建了一张桌子 一张空桌子 然后我就
assign at table, at that string, true.
在表中 在该字符串处赋值为真
And then I can just query that table.
然后我就可以查询那个表了
Do I have a key player and a key alien?
我有关键球员和关键外星人吗？
Do I have a key obstacle and a key obstacle?
我有一个关键障碍和一个关键障碍吗？
This is how you can figure out what your two objects were.
这就是您可以计算出您的两个对象是什么的方法
Because A could be a player and B can be an obstacle.
因为A可能是一个球员 而B可能是一个障碍
A can be an obstacle and B could be the player.
A可以是障碍 B可以是球员
So you have to take both of that into consideration.
所以你必须把这两点都考虑进去
So it allows us to do if types obstacle and types player, so
所以它允许我们这样做 如果类型障碍和类型球员 所以
a collision between the player and an obstacle, if it's fast enough, then we
球员与障碍物的碰撞 如果速度足够快 那么我们
can destroy the obstacle.
可以摧毁障碍物
This is what we do here.
这就是我们在这里做的事情
So I take the absolute value of the velocity on the X and Y.
所以我取X和Y轴上速度的绝对值
So I do vel X vel Y gets the body's linear velocity.
所以我计算 X Y 得到物体的线速度
So linear velocity is just where it's moving in the world.
所以线速度就是它在世界上移动的地方
And it returns two values because velocity has an X and Y component.
它返回两个值 因为速度有X和Y分量
And then we sum it here by taking its absolute value of both parts
然后我们在这里求和 取两部分的绝对值
and adding it together.
然后把它们加在一起
So if it's moving fast on the x-axis, but not fast on the y-axis,
因此 如果它在x轴上移动得很快 但在y轴上移动得不快
or if it's not moving fast on either, or if it's moving fast on both,
或者如果它在两个方向上都没有快速移动 或者如果它在两个方向上都快速移动
we have a sense, in general, what's the average velocity of our object.
一般来说 我们有一个感觉 物体的平均速度是多少
If it's moving fast on any of the axes, we
如果它在任一轴上快速移动 我们
can assume that that's sufficient force to cause an object
可以假设这是足够的力来导致物体
to get destroyed, right?
会被毁掉 对吧？
So we do if the velocity is greater than 20, just an arbitrary value
如果速度大于20 我们就会这样做 这是一个任意值
that I came up with that seemed appropriate,
我想出的那个似乎是合适的
then we're going to do this.
然后我们就要这么做了
Table dot insert self dot destroyed bodies, which we saw earlier.
桌子圆点插入自我圆点毁灭的身体 这是我们之前看到的
And then the obstacles body.
然后是障碍物的身体
Now, why are we inserting that value here as
现在 为什么我们在这里插入该值为
opposed to, maybe just destroying it inside this function?
反对 也许只是在这个函数中销毁它？
AUDIENCE: Destroying the fixture.
观众：破坏灯具
COLTON OGDEN: Destroying the body.
科尔顿·奥格登：毁灭肉体
The fixture, yeah, in this case.
固定装置 是的 在这种情况下
AUDIENCE: I mean the fixture, sorry.
观众：对不起 我是说这场比赛
Because you're still referencing it later in the code.
因为您稍后仍会在代码中引用它
COLTON OGDEN: You're still referencing later in the code.
Colton Ogden：您在代码的后面仍在引用
Box2D maintains a reference to all of the bodies, all
Box2D维护对所有Body、All
of the fixtures in your world, regardless of
你的世界中的固定装置 而不管
whether you've deleted them or not.
不管你有没有删除它们
But if you delete them while it's in the middle of a,
但是如果你在它正在运行的时候把它们删除
like checking for collision, it'll try to do another collision
就像检查冲突一样 它会尝试进行另一次冲突
with that destroyed body and you'll get a crash or a stack overflow error.
使用被销毁的主体 您将得到崩溃或堆栈溢出错误
I found I experienced both of those.
我发现这两件事我都经历过
You don't want to ever delete or destroy anything while inside a collision
你不会想要在碰撞中删除或销毁任何东西
callback for your world.
回拨你的世界
It will cause horrible things to happen.
它会导致可怕的事情发生
So what we do is we maintain a reference to everything that we're
所以我们所做的就是保持对我们所做的一切的引用
going to destroy by just inserting it.
只要把它插进去就会毁了它
So if we do table dot insert the body of whatever we want into destroyed bodies,
所以如果我们把我们想要的任何东西的身体放进被销毁的身体里
we can then loop over that after the world updates.
然后 我们可以在世界更新后对其进行循环
And then just destroy them one by one outside of the update function.
然后在更新函数之外逐个销毁它们
And the reason that we are passing in the body and not the fixture
我们通过身体而不是固定装置的原因
is when we destroy a body, it destroys all the fixtures
当我们摧毁一具身体时 它就摧毁了所有的固定装置
associated with that body as well.
也与那具身体有关
So we're just destroying the top level container here.
所以我们只是在摧毁这里的顶层集装箱
In this case, it doesn't matter too much whether we destroy a fixture or a body
在这种情况下 我们是销毁一个固定装置还是销毁一个身体并不重要
because it's a one to one relationship.
因为这是一对一的关系
But if you had, let's say, a body that has five fixtures on it.
但如果你有 比方说 一个身体上有五个固定物
And if that entire thing collides with something else
如果这整个东西和别的东西相撞
and you want to destroy that entire thing,
你想毁掉这一切
you want to destroy the body, not an individual fixture.
你想毁掉的是尸体而不是一个人
Because when you destroy the body, it destroys all the fixtures, not just
因为当你摧毁尸体的时候 它摧毁了所有的固定装置 而不仅仅是
the one fixture.
唯一的固定装置
So that's we're deleting the body, adding the body to destroyed bodies,
所以我们删除了尸体 把尸体加到被摧毁的尸体上
and then later performing a delete off of that.
然后再删除
The function is destroy here.
函数在这里被销毁
So on line 157--
所以在157行--
well, 155 to 159, this is where we actually
从155到159 这就是我们
iterate over everything that we wanted to flag,
把所有我们想标记的东西都盖上
or that we've flagged as destroyed, and we destroy it.
或者我们标记为已销毁的 然后销毁
So if not body is destroyed, destroy it.
如果身体没有被摧毁 那就摧毁它
And then once we destroy it, we're going to go down here and end up
一旦我们摧毁了它 我们就到这里
actually removing the obstacle and the alien class
实际上消除了障碍和外星人阶级
from our list of aliens and obstacles.
从我们的外星人和障碍物列表中删除
Because that maintains a reference to what we're drawing
因为它保持了我们所画的
and we want to also delete that.
我们也想删除它
So not only do we want to delete the object from the world,
所以我们不仅想从世界上删除这个物体
we want to delete the objects that we've created
我们要删除我们创建的对象
that are a wrapper for the bodies and fixtures
用来包装尸体和固定装置
and also the drawing of our aliens so it no longer gets drawn to the scene,
还有外星人的画像 这样它就不会再被吸引到这个场景
basically.
基本上
So yeah, don't ever delete a body or a fixture inside your callbacks.
所以 永远不要删除回调函数中的body或fixture
Always flag them and delete them afterwards.
总是标记它们 然后删除它们
Basically, don't delete in the middle of a world update function
基本上 不要在世界更新功能的中间删除
call, which we see here.
这就是我们在这里看到的
Notice that this takes place, 152, were doing self world update.
请注意 这发生在152 正在进行自我世界更新
And then on 155 to 159, we've populated destroyed bodies via the collision
然后在155到159 我们通过碰撞填充了被摧毁的身体
callback that we defined up above.
我们在上面定义的回调
So in here, this is where we can actually destroy everything.
在这里 我们可以摧毁一切
This is outside of the update function, here, the world update function.
这是更新功能之外的 这里是世界更新功能
We don't need to worry about stack overflow or a segfault, which
我们不需要担心堆栈溢出或segfault
we get by deleting something while it's in the middle
我们可以删除中间的内容
of processing its collisions.
来处理碰撞
So unfortunate bug.
不幸的bug
If you ever find yourself running into stack overflows or segfaults
如果您发现自己遇到了堆栈溢出或段错误
in your collision callbacks, make sure you're not deleting anything.
在冲突回调中 请确保没有删除任何内容
But we can see here, it's very similar, the behavior
但我们可以在这里看到 它非常相似 行为
we defined between obstacles and the player, between obstacles and aliens,
我们定义了障碍和玩家之间 障碍和外星人之间
and between the player and alien.
以及玩家和外星人之间的关系
Ultimately, it's check to see whether the average of its velocity
最终 它要检查的是它的平均速度
is greater than a certain number, in this case, 20.
大于某个数字 在本例中为20
And if it is, flag it as destroyed.
如果是 则将其标记为已销毁
So if the player hits the alien, destroy it.
因此 如果玩家击中外星人 摧毁它
If a obstacle hits
如果障碍物击中外星人 摧毁它
And it's similar to how it works in Angry Birds.
这与《愤怒的小鸟》中的工作原理相似
When you throw something at a structure in Angry Birds and a piece of debris
当你在《愤怒的小鸟》中向建筑物扔东西和一块碎片时
falls off of it and hits the pig, usually kills the pig too.
从它上掉下来撞到猪 通常也会杀死猪
And if your bird hits the pig, that usually kills the pig.
如果你的鸟撞上了猪 通常会杀死猪
But if you're not moving fast enough or if a piece of debris
但如果你移动得不够快 或者如果一块碎片
isn't moving fast enough, it'll just nudge the pig,
移动得还不够快 它只会轻推猪
it won't actually kill the pig.
它实际上不会杀死那头猪
So that's why we're taking all of this into consideration.
这就是为什么我们要把所有这些都考虑进去
We're not just doing a blind delete off of the body's in our code,
我们不仅仅是在代码中盲目删除身体的内容
we're actually making sure, is it also moving fast enough, i.e.
我们实际上是在确定 它的移动速度是否也足够快 即
does it have enough force?
它有足够的力量吗？
And if it does, then perform the code, then perform the deletion or flag it
如果是 则执行代码 然后执行删除或标记
as being deleted.
已被删除
And so once again, that's why user data is important.
因此 这就是为什么用户数据很重要的原因
Because that's how we're able to-- because notice in the callback
因为这就是我们能够--因为在回调中注意到
we just get an A and a B. And those are always going to be fixtures.
我们只得到了A和B 而这些将永远是固定的
Fixtures, in order for it to know what kind of a fixture
固定装置 以便它知道是哪种固定装置
it is, whether it belongs to a player or an alien,
它是 无论它属于玩家还是外星人
we need to give it some information.
我们需要给它一些信息
So the set user data flags the fixtures as being of a specific type.
因此 设置的用户数据将装置标记为特定类型
And then we can fetch it here with get user data
然后我们可以使用Get User Data在这里获取它
and then actually perform the relevant game logic.
然后实际执行相关的博弈逻辑
Any questions as to how this works?
对于这是如何工作的 有什么问题吗？
AUDIENCE: Are you checking for if two obstacles knock into each other?
观众：你是在检查两个障碍物是否相撞吗？
COLTON OGDEN: Am I checking with two obstacles collide with each other?
科尔顿·奥格登：我是在检查两个相互碰撞的障碍物吗？
I might not be.
我可能不是
In that case-- you should.
如果是那样的话--你应该这样做
In that case, since we're not, they'll just bump into each other.
在这种情况下 既然我们不是 他们就会撞在一起
But, yeah, if we wanted two wooden obstacles
但是 是的 如果我们想要两个木制障碍
to destroy each other if they hit fast enough,
如果他们打得足够快的话就会互相摧毁
you would just do the same thing here.
你在这里也会做同样的事情
If types obstacle, I guess.
如果类型有障碍 我想
But in this case, because they're both the same key,
但在这种情况下 因为它们都是同一把钥匙
you would have to do if types--
你必须做的是 如果类型--
let's see how we're doing it again.
让我们看看我们怎么再做一次
So types obstacles is true, types obstacles is true.
所以类型障碍是真的 类型障碍是真的
You would say if types obstacle and not types alien, not types player, not--
你会说如果类型障碍而不是外星人类型 不是类型玩家 不是--
there's a cleaner way to do it.
有一种更干净的方法来做这件事
AUDIENCE: Like a series of [INAUDIBLE] statements.
观众：就像一系列的[INAUDIBLE]声明
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] statements.
观众：[听不见]陈述
That's true.
那是真的
Yeah, there's a lot of ways.
是啊 有很多种方法
And if I were to re-engineer this, I would also abstract out this code
如果我要重新设计这个 我也会抽象出这个代码
and make it a function.
并把它变成一个函数
Because it's pretty much the same code between all three of these.
因为这三者之间的代码基本相同
But just to illustrate and just for simplicity
但为了说明 为了简单起见
because it's pretty similar interactions,
因为这是非常相似的互动
didn't really put too much engineering forethought into it.
并没有真正在其中投入太多的工程预见性
Definitely if you expand upon it, I would recommend doing that.
当然 如果您对它进行扩展 我会建议您这样做
But that's the gist of making our world behave beyond just resolving
但这是让我们的世界表现得不仅仅是解决
collisions and pushing obstacles away from each other, which
碰撞和相互推开障碍物 这
is the default behavior.
是默认行为
So we set the callbacks.
所以我们设置了回调
We're good.
我们很好
Now things, when we interact with each other, they'll behave differently,
现在 当我们彼此互动时 它们的行为会有所不同
they'll trigger different behavior.
它们会引发不同的行为
We have this thing called a launch marker, an alien launch marker.
我们有一个叫发射标志的东西 一个外星人发射标志
Anybody know what that might be?
有人知道这可能是什么吗？
AUDIENCE: Is that the little dots that show the trajectory?
观众：这是显示轨迹的小圆点吗？
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah, so it's the dots that show the trajectory.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的 所以是圆点显示了轨迹
It's one, the alien being rendered on the left side of the screen
这是一个 外星人被渲染在屏幕的左侧
without any physics applied to it, that's click and dragable.
没有任何物理作用 那就是点击和拖动
And it also renders a trajectory.
它也会呈现出一个轨迹
And when you release the mouse, it launches an actual Box2D alien
当你松开鼠标时 它会发射一个真正的Box 2D外星人
traveling in the direction that that trajectory foretells.
沿着轨迹所预示的方向移动
If we look at alien launch marker here, it basically maintains a reference to
如果我们看这里的外星人发射标记 它基本上保持了一个参考
whether we're aiming or not.
不管我们有没有瞄准
So it's got a couple of states.
所以它有几个州
It's got a launch state and an aiming state.
它有发射状态和瞄准状态
An alien that we'll have a reference to eventually, which
我们最终会找到一个外星人
will spawn and will give it an impulse.
会产生并给它一个动力
So an impulse is effectively setting its velocity immediately to some value,
所以一个脉冲有效地将它的速度立即设置为某个值
as opposed to something over time.
而不是随着时间的推移
We can apply force to an object, which would
我们可以对物体施力
be like you driving your car up against something
就像你开车撞上了什么东西
and then gradually accelerating, that's applying force.
然后逐渐加速 这就是施加力
And we can also apply impulse by going full speed with our car
我们也可以通过汽车全速行驶来施加冲力
and hitting an object, and that will have
撞击一个物体
the effect of applying an impulse at a certain velocity.
以一定速度施加脉冲的效果
When we drag our alien and then we release it,
当我们拖着外星人然后把它放了
we want to apply an impulse in the opposite direction of where we're
我们要在相反的方向施加一个脉冲
dragging based on a certain amount.
基于一定量的拖动
I scaled it by 10, but you can have it be arbitrary.
我把它放大了10倍 但你可以让它任意放大
And then the trajectory models where it's going.
然后弹道模型会显示出它的去向
And the trajectory is calculated via these lines here.
轨迹是通过这些线计算出来的
So from line 90 to 104.
从第90行到第104行
There is a formula for, in that Box2D set
在Box 2D集合中有一个公式
of tutorials, that actually shows you how
的教程 这实际上告诉你如何
to calculate an estimated trajectory given a starting impulse and a starting
为了计算给定启动脉冲和启动脉冲的估计轨迹
position.
位置
Which is this formula here.
也就是这个公式
It's semi-complicated.
有点复杂
The article goes into detail as to how it works,
这篇文章详细介绍了它是如何工作的
but it effectively calculates 1/60 of a second,
但它有效地计算了1/60秒
assuming that we're running our simulation at 1/60 of a second,
假设我们以1/60秒的速度进行模拟
it will, over 90 iterations here, 1 to 90,
它将在这里进行90次迭代 从1到90
calculate each individual step of that simulation.
计算模拟的每一步
And then I only render every 5 here.
然后我在这里只渲染每5个
So if i is mod 5 s 0, then I'll actually end up
所以如果i是mod 5s 那么我最终会得到
drawing a circle at trajectory X, trajectory
在轨迹X处绘制圆 轨迹
Y. Trajectory X and Y being here.
轨迹X和Y在这里
Shifted X, shifted Y being the starting location.
平移了X 平移了Y作为起始位置
And then we multiply i by 1/60 of a second, which will give us
然后我们将I乘以1/60秒 这将得到
the scalar for this impulse here.
这里是这个脉冲的标量
And then with gravity we have to do this i squared plus
然后在重力的作用下 我们必须做这个 我的平方加
i times 1/2 times the gravity on the y-axis times 1/60 squared.
I乘以y轴上重力的1/2乘以1/60的平方
The article goes into a little bit more detail as to how it works.
这篇文章更详细地介绍了它的工作原理
But that's it converted into source code.
但这就是它被转换成源代码的原因
But it's effectively a gravity simulation
但这实际上是一种重力模拟
and a velocity simulation over time.
以及随时间变化的速度模拟
And by rendering it based on 90 iterations, which
并通过基于90次迭代来呈现它 这
is one and a half seconds, at 1/60 of a second
是1.5秒 也就是1/60秒
we can forecast where exactly we're going.
我们可以准确地预测我们要去哪里
And then when we apply this impulse, X and Y, the ball will actually travel,
然后当我们施加这个脉冲 X和Y时 球实际上会移动
the alien will actually travel in that direction at that exact trajectory.
外星人实际上会以那个准确的轨迹朝那个方向移动
That's the complicated part of the launch marker.
这是发射标志的复杂部分
The other part is that it has a couple of states, like I said before.
另一部分是它有几个州 就像我之前说的那样
So when we click and we're not launched, it should go into aiming mode.
因此 当我们点击时 我们没有发射 它应该进入瞄准模式
And so if we're aiming then we're going to set a rotation to--
所以如果我们瞄准了 我们就会设置一个旋转来--
actually, rotation is not relevant because this was before I ended up
实际上 轮换并不重要 因为这是在我结束之前
using the predictive trajectory method.
使用预测轨迹方法
The shift at X and Y though, those are relevant because that's the starting
然而 X和Y处的移动是相关的 因为这是开始
location for your trajectory.
你的轨迹的位置
That's wherever your mouse is.
这就是你的鼠标所在的位置
And we clamp it so that it doesn't go past a certain limit
我们夹住它 这样它就不会超过一定的极限
on the left or the right, so that it stays within a box area.
在左边或右边 这样它就会留在方框区域内
But this will be whenever you let go of the mouse, that
但这将是当你放开鼠标的时候
will be where we spawn the Box2D alien and apply
将是我们孕育Box2D外星人并应用
an impulse in a negative direction relative to where we move the mouse.
相对于我们移动鼠标的位置向负方向的冲动
So if we move the mouse to the left and down,
因此 如果我们将鼠标向左向下移动
it's going to negate that with an impulse going up
它将用一种上升的冲动来否定这一点
and to the right, if that makes sense.
向右 如果这有意义的话
And that's what's shown by the trajectory.
这就是轨迹所显示的
And then, aside from that, it renders different things
除此之外 它还呈现了不同的东西
depending on whether or not--
取决于是否--
what state we're in.
我们现在处于什么状态
So if we haven't launched, it will render just the alien.
因此 如果我们没有发射 它将只渲染外星人
If we're in aiming mode then it should actually render and calculate
如果我们处于瞄准模式 那么它实际上应该渲染并计算
the trajectory.
弹道
Otherwise, it would just render the alien.
否则 它只会渲染外星人
And so once we release the mouse, so was released 1 and were aiming,
所以一旦我们释放了鼠标 我们就释放了1并瞄准了它
launched is true, spawn an alien.
发射是真的 生一个外星人
So we create a new alien with self world, it's round.
所以我们创造了一个新的外星人和自我世界 它是圆的
We started at shifted X and shifted Y. We
我们从换X换到换Y开始 我们
set its linear velocity to the same values that we calculated before.
将其线速度设置为我们之前计算的相同值
So it's base X minus shifted X times 10.
所以它是基数X减去移位X乘以10
So the times 10 is a scalar amount.
所以 乘以10是一个标量
And then the base X is where we've moved it, effectively.
然后 基数X实际上就是我们移动它的地方
Or, no.
或者 不是
Base X is where it starts and shifted X is where we've moved it.
基数X是它开始的地方 移位X是我们移动它的地方
And so by subtracting shifted from the base,
因此 通过从基数减去移位
we get the negative direction that we want to effect the impulse.
我们得到了我们想要影响冲动的负面方向
And then the impulse is set here with linear velocity.
然后在这里设置冲量 线速度
And then we also set it to have a restitution of 0.4.
然后我们也将其设置为恢复原状为0.4
Recall, restitution is bounciness.
回想一下 恢复原状就是反弹
So our alien bounces a little bit when it hits the ground.
所以我们的外星人在落地时会反弹一点
And then anybody know what angular damping might be?
然后有人知道角衰减可能是什么吗？
Any guesses?
有没有人猜到？
Angular damping is when it rotates, basically, friction on its rotation.
角阻尼是指当它旋转时 基本上是它旋转时的摩擦力
So that when it rotates on the ground, it doesn't roll indefinitely.
因此 当它在地面上旋转时 它不会无限滚动
If we don't set that, it'll just roll forever and ever and ever and ever.
如果我们不设置 它只会永远地滚动
Which is not what we want.
这不是我们想要的
We want it to stop at a certain point because once it stops,
我们希望它在某个时间点停止 因为一旦它停止
we know, OK, now we can get the next alien ready to launch.
我们知道 好了 现在我们可以让下一个外星人准备发射了
And that's the gist behind the launch marker.
这就是发射标志背后的主旨
How we render trajectory.
我们如何呈现轨迹
For the math on that, a little bit more in detail, I would explore that URL.
对于这方面的计算 更详细地说 我将探索该URL
It goes into it into pretty good detail.
它深入到了非常好的细节中
I use that as a reference for creating this bit of code here.
我在这里使用它作为创建这段代码的参考
But yeah, effectively, is it's just rendering
但实际上 它只是在渲染
a bunch of circles with that trajectory and calculating it
一堆有这个轨迹的圆 然后计算它
over 90 ticks, 90 frame iterations.
超过90个刻度 90帧迭代
Back to the level.
回到那一层
Sorry, any questions overall as to how the launch marker works?
对不起 关于发射标记的整体工作原理有什么问题吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
观众：没有
COLTON OGDEN: Cool.
科尔顿·奥格登：酷
All right.
好的
So then we have an alien's table, an obstacles table,
所以我们有一个外星人的桌子 一个障碍物桌子
edge shape for the ground.
地面的边缘形状
And then we just create an alien to destroy.
然后我们只需创造一个外星人来摧毁
Spawn a few obstacles here.
在这里制造一些障碍
So in this case, two vertical obstacles and a horizontal one.
在这种情况下 有两个垂直障碍物和一个水平障碍物
Positioned such that the horizontal one is over the vertical ones
定位成水平的在垂直的上方
and they're spaced apart such that the aliens are in the middle of them.
它们是分开的 所以外星人就在它们中间
Then the ground here, we give the ground some friction, 0.5.
然后这里的地面 我们给地面一些摩擦 0.5
And that's pretty much it for setting up our level.
这很大程度上是为了建立我们的水平
So if we wanted to, after this point, we have the foundation
所以 如果我们想 在这一点之后 我们有了基础
necessary to really spawn arbitrary levels with admittedly simple obstacles
必须使用公认简单的障碍才能真正产生任意级别
at this point.
在这点上
But we could set--
但我们可以设定--
because all we're doing here is just simple insertions to our aliens
因为我们在这里所做的只是简单地插入我们的外星人
and obstacles table, we could create pretty much any level just by, maybe
和障碍物桌 我们可以创建几乎任何关卡 也许
in data, specifying level could be like a table
在数据中 指定级别可能类似于表
and then aliens could be another table.
然后外星人可能会成为另一张桌子
And then maybe all it is just a like X equals some value,
然后可能只是X等于某个值
and then Y equals some value.
然后Y等于某个值
And then obstacles is the same thing.
然后障碍也是一回事
And then all we do is just we iterate over this level definition
然后我们所要做的就是迭代这个级别的定义
and we just say, new alien for every table here.
我们只是说 这里的每一张桌子都有新的外星人
And then new obstacle for every table in here.
然后这里的每一张桌子都有了新的障碍
And then now your levels are data driven.
然后现在你的水平是由数据驱动的
It's easy just to make levels.
只需调整级别就很容易了
You don't have to code, really, much.
你不需要编写代码 真的 很多
And you can put this in a separate file.
你可以把它放在一个单独的文件里
Be like, levels dot Lua, and then just load individual levels at a time.
就像 关卡点缀Lua 然后一次只加载单独的关卡
Level 1 equals-- levels would be the top level container.
级别1等于--级别将是顶级容器
And then you would have 1 equals all of this, and then 2
然后你会得到1等于所有这些 然后是2
equals another one, 3 equals another one.
等于另一个 3等于另一个
And then you're not really programming as much
然后你就不会真的编程那么多了
as you are just laying things out in data.
因为你只是在数据中展示事物
Super nice and concise.
超级漂亮和简洁
That's a nice thing about a language like Lua, is that you can,
这是像Lua这样的语言的一件好事 就是你可以
and it's the same thing in JavaScript with JSON,
在JSON中的Java脚本中也是如此
you can just define things as data and then write
您可以将事物定义为数据 然后编写
a script to go over it and construct your actual relevant data structures
一个脚本来遍历它并构建您实际相关的数据结构
that way--
这样一来
in your code that way.
在您的代码中以这种方式
When you have the foundation like we have now
当你有了像我们现在这样的基础
where you can think in terms of obstacles and aliens,
在那里你可以从障碍和外星人的角度来思考
you can construct levels like so.
您可以像这样构建关卡
And obviously you could go a lot more complicated with this.
显然 你可以用这个做得更复杂
All we're doing is having very simple almost boring static obstacles.
我们所做的只是一些非常简单、几乎令人厌烦的静态障碍
They're not static in a technical sense because they're dynamic objects,
它们在技术意义上不是静态的 因为它们是动态对象
but all they really do is just stand there and then fall over.
但他们真正做的就是站在那里 然后摔倒
But if you wanted a pulley system or maybe
但如果你想要滑轮系统或者
something that's shaped in a giant head or something,
一种被塑造成一个巨大的头部的东西
you can create arbitrarily complex objects that way using joints.
可以使用关节以这种方式创建任意复杂的对象
And if you're curious, I recommend to look into the documentation for Love2D
如果你很好奇 我建议你去看看Love2D的文档
a little bit more.
再多一点
Especially their weld joints are what you would use
尤其是他们的焊接接头是你会用到的
to combine pieces in arbitrary shapes.
把碎片组合成任意形状
But you could easily take this to the next level
但你可以很容易地把这一点带到下一个层次
and start to create in that same level definition, arbitrarily shaped,
并开始在相同的层次定义中创建 任意形状
welded together obstacles.
把障碍物焊接在一起
But that would be, I think, a next step if you're looking
但我认为 这将是下一步 如果你想
to take this beyond just one level.
让这一点超越一个层次
I would say, think in terms of, how can I get my game world represented
我会说 想一想 我如何才能让我的游戏世界得到展示
in a very simple data like way?
以一种非常简单的数据方式？
Because not only does it make it easier for you to create content,
因为它不仅让您更容易创建内容
it allows you to shift that burden to somebody else
它允许你将负担转嫁给其他人
and allow you to give the task of creating levels
并允许您将创建关卡的任务交给
less to a programmer and maybe more to somebody
对程序员来说更少 对某人来说可能更多
who has just a design background who isn't as comfortable writing code.
他只有一个设计背景 对编写代码不是很在行
And allow you to create the engine that constructs the game world based off
并允许您创建引擎来构建基于
of this data.
这些数据
Any questions as to how we've set things up here?
对我们是怎么安排的有什么问题吗？
OK.
好的
So we have the ground, we have a background.
所以我们有了背景 我们有了背景
A background is just a simple class that renders a static image
背景只是一个呈现静态图像的简单类
that you can scroll the image with left or right,
你可以用左或右滚动图像
but we don't end up using it much.
但我们最终并不经常使用它
It's relevant in Angry Birds because in Angry Birds they have a camera,
这与《愤怒的小鸟》相关 因为《愤怒的小鸟》里有摄像头
and the camera pans left to right depending on how far away
摄像机会根据距离从左到右摇摄
the fortress is from your sling shot.
堡垒是从你的弹弓上射出的
So that's in there if you want to experiment with it at all,
所以如果你想要做实验的话 这就是你的想法
and experiment with a moving camera.
并用一个移动的相机进行实验
Maybe use timer dot tween to tween the camera
也许可以使用定时器点补间来补间相机
or just to have it track the alien if you want larger worlds.
或者只是让它追踪外星人 如果你想要更大的世界
But we don't end up using it in the distro as much.
但我们在发行版中使用它的次数并不多
Our update function is simple.
我们的更新功能很简单
We update the launch marker, update the world,
我们更新发射标志 更新世界
and then we process all the bodies that we flagged as being destroyed,
然后我们处理所有我们标记为已销毁的身体
which we've already seen.
我们已经看到了这一点
We reset destroyed bodies to an empty table
我们把被销毁的身体放在一张空桌子上
because we've processed all of them.
因为我们已经全部处理过了
We actually remove from our level the obstacle objects
我们实际上把障碍物从我们的水平线上移走
so that they're no longer rendered, and we no longer
所以它们不再被渲染 我们也不再
try to reference the bodies that are destroyed.
试着参考那些被销毁的身体
And then notice here too, when we destroy the obstacle,
然后注意 当我们摧毁障碍物时
we're playing a sound effect inside this bit of code.
我们在这段代码中播放音效
So we can just do g sounds.
所以我们可以只做G音
I put five wooden sound effects in there just for variability.
我在里面放了五个木制音效 只是为了变化无常
It'll pick a random one.
它会随机挑选一个
And then using to string at the number, just
然后用来串起数字 只需
create break one, two, three, four, five here.
在这里创造一 二 三 四 五
And then stop and play it.
然后停下来播放它
Same thing here.
这里也是一样
I have a sound called kill for when we destroy an alien.
我有一种声音叫当我们消灭外星人时的杀戮
So when we flag an alien as destroyed and we remove it from the scene,
所以当我们将一个外星人标记为毁灭并将其从场景中移走时
we should also call that sound effect.
我们也应该称之为音效
And then if the alien stops moving in our scene, the player,
然后如果外星人停止在我们的场景中移动 玩家
we can get a reference to it here, self dot launch marker dot alien,
我们可以在这里找到它的参考 自助点发射标记点外星人
as opposed to any aliens in our scene.
而不是我们场景中的任何外星人
When it stops moving, so we get the average of its velocity
当它停止运动时 我们就得到了它的平均速度
and if it's less than 1.5, so not perfectly
如果它低于1.5 那么就不是很完美
still, because it's tedious to wait that long, but almost still,
尽管如此 因为等待那么长时间是乏味的 但几乎还是如此
we destroy the alien and then we create a new launch marker.
我们摧毁外星人 然后创建一个新的发射标志
We destroy the alien so that the world doesn't keep a reference to it
我们摧毁外星人 这样世界就不会再提及它
and then we just create a brand new marker,
然后我们只需创建一个全新的标记
which has the effect of instantiating a new alien there when we relaunch.
它的作用是在我们重新启动时在那里实例化一个新的外星人
And then here, if there are no more aliens in our scene,
在这里 如果我们的场景中没有更多的外星人
if we've destroyed all of the aliens, in this case there's only ever one,
如果我们摧毁了所有的外星人 在这种情况下只有一个
but there could easily, with a little more work,
但是 只要多做一点工作 就可以很容易地做到
be a few more aliens in the scene, if it's set to zero,
在场景中再增加几个外星人 如果设置为零
then go back to the start.
然后回到起点
Which we saw before when we finally killed the alien.
当我们最终杀死外星人时我们看到了这一点
And then all we're doing here is deferring
然后我们在这里所做的就是推迟
rendering to the individual objects we want to render, the launch marker,
渲染到我们要渲染的各个对象、启动标记、
the alien, the obstacle.
外星人 障碍
We render ground tiles.
我们绘制地砖
So recall, from our ground example before we were just using a line,
回想一下 从我们之前的地面示例中 我们只使用了一行
an edge shape to represent the ground.
表示地面的边形状
But if we look at our game, it's a little hard to see because I'm in 720,
但如果我们看看我们的比赛 这就有点难看出了 因为我是720
but there's actually a ground tile here at the very bottom, a bunch of them.
但实际上在底部有一块地砖 有一堆
And even though we have all of those tiles,
即使我们有所有的瓷砖
all we're doing to detect collision is just an edge shape.
我们所做的只是检测碰撞的边缘形状
So what we're doing is just beyond having the edge shape in our scene,
因此 我们所做的不仅仅是场景中的边缘形状
we draw that tile, which is frame 12 in our sprite sheet
我们绘制该瓷砖 它是精灵工作表中的第12帧
from negative virtual width to virtual times 2.
从负虚拟宽度到虚拟时间2
So three screen widths total.
所以总共有三个屏幕宽度
And then we just do it in increments of 35 pixels
然后我们只需以35像素为增量
because that's how wide the tile is.
因为这就是瓷砖的宽度
And that'll just create a bunch of the same tile
这只会产生一堆相同的瓷砖
at the very bottom of our screen.
在我们屏幕的最底部
So just a graphical thing, not really necessarily functional.
所以只是一个图形化的东西 并不是真的有功能
We have the edge shape already in our scene, but just to make the ground
我们的场景中已经有了边缘形状 但只是为了铺设地面
look a little larger than one pixel tall.
看起来比一个像素高一点
And then if we haven't launched anything,
如果我们还没有发射任何东西
we should display some instructions here.
我们应该在这里显示一些说明
And then if we're at no aliens left, then we
然后如果我们没有外星人留下 那么我们
should display the victory screen.
应显示胜利屏幕
And the victory thing will last for just a little bit of time,
胜利的事情只会持续一小段时间
because even though self dot aliens is zero, this bit of code
因为即使自我点状的外星人是零 这一点代码
doesn't register until after the velocity of our moving alien
直到我们移动的外星人的速度
slows down sufficiently.
减速到足够慢
So this will get called when we're just about to finally stop moving,
所以 当我们最终要停止移动时 这将会被调用
and then we check to see, oh, OK, do we indeed have no aliens left?
然后我们检查一下 哦 好的 我们真的没有外星人了吗？
If not, time to go back to the start.
如果不是 那么是时候回到起点了
We've completed a level.
我们已经完成了一个关卡
And then you obviously would just change this
然后很明显你会改变这一点
to go to be next level if you ended up implementing more
如果您最终实现了更多 则进入下一个级别
levels in your game besides just one.
在你的游戏中只有一个级别
Beyond that, that's pretty much all of the code that's in this example.
除此之外 这几乎就是本例中的所有代码
It's fairly, I would say, unsophisticated relative
我想说 这是一个相当朴素的亲戚
to prior examples.
之前的例子
But mainly, the burden is learning how to use
但主要的负担是学习如何使用
the physics engine, the Box2D physics engine, which
物理引擎 Box2D物理引擎 它
itself is quite a few functions.
本身就是相当多的函数
It's some of the longest documentation on Love2D's wiki, I think.
我认为这是Love2D维基上最长的文档
But the principles are pretty simple, in my opinion.
但在我看来 这些原则非常简单
I think it's actually quite easy to get rolling with a lot of cool features.
我认为 有了很多很酷的功能 其实很容易上手
The vast majority of which I don't think we even really cover,
我认为我们甚至没有真正涵盖其中的绝大多数
at least in terms of what you can do with compound objects and joints
至少在可以对复合对象和关节执行的操作方面
and things like that, which really start to go
诸如此类的事情 真的开始
into the world of more sophisticated and interesting physical simulations.
进入更复杂、更有趣的物理模拟世界
Things like I alluded to before, pulleys and tanks and other things like that.
就像我之前提到的滑轮和坦克之类的东西
Some features that we could look at potentially expanding upon
一些我们可以考虑潜在扩展的功能
if we wanted to make our game more interesting,
如果我们想让我们的游戏更有趣
is more shapes for our objects.
是为我们的对象提供更多的形状
So if we look at our sprite sheet here, we
所以 如果我们看一下这里的精灵图 我们
can see there are things like roofs and circles and things like that.
可以看到有屋顶和圆圈之类的东西
So more interesting obstacles beyond just square rectangular
所以除了正方形之外还有更多有趣的障碍
shaped obstacles.
有形状的障碍
Go back to-- like I said before, compound obstacles.
回到--就像我之前说的 复合障碍
So a bunch of things put together via joints.
所以一堆东西通过关节组合在一起
So pulleys, there's motors, weld joints, which you can use to-- you
所以滑轮 有马达 焊接接头 你可以用来--你
can affix a roof to a square and then have two pieces that are tied together.
可以将屋顶固定在正方形上 然后将两块绑在一起
And you can make arbitrarily complex and shaped things
你可以制造出任意复杂和有形状的东西
and just be really interesting.
而且真的很有趣
And that big thing, that body with all these fixtures,
还有那个很大的东西 有这么多固定装置的身体
will collide just as any other thing would, thanks to Box2D.
会发生碰撞 就像任何其他东西一样 这要归功于Box2D
As I alluded to before, instead of having levels to be hard coded
正如我之前提到的 不是硬编码级别
into our level class, maybe define them in a Lua file called levels dot Lua.
到我们的Level类中 也许可以在一个名为LevelsDot Lua的Lua文件中定义它们
And then just have aliens be a table, obstacles
然后让外星人成为一张桌子 障碍
be a table, and then whatever else, however
是一张桌子 然后是其他任何东西 然而
more complicated you want to get with your game.
你想用你的游戏变得更复杂
You can add more things.
您可以添加更多内容
But just have it be represented as simple data structures.
但只要将其表示为简单的数据结构即可
So aliens that maybe have different shooting mechanics.
所以外星人可能有不同的射击机制
So if you've played Angry Birds you're familiar with the fact
所以 如果你玩过《愤怒的小鸟》 你就会熟悉这样一个事实
that some birds will split off into multiple birds.
一些鸟会分裂成多只鸟
Some birds will dive and go super fast and break through all the obstacles
有些鸟会以超快的速度俯冲 冲破所有的障碍
in their path.
挡在他们的道路上
Some birds will explode, and then their explosion
一些鸟会爆炸 然后它们的爆炸
affects all of the obstacles around them.
影响他们周围的所有障碍物
So there's a lot of different game play mechanics
所以有很多不同的游戏机制
you can implement using different types of birds or aliens.
您可以使用不同类型的鸟类或外星人来实现
And then different obstacle materials is another direction we could go.
然后 不同的障碍材料是我们可以尝试的另一个方向
And it's supported out of the box with the sprite sheet
它开箱即用精灵薄片支撑
that I provided because it has sheets for metal
这是我提供的 因为它有金属板
and glass and explosive material.
玻璃和爆炸性材料
So there's a lot of different interesting things
所以有很多不同的有趣的东西
you could do just by changing up what materials you're using in the game.
你只需要改变你在游戏中使用的材料就可以了
And obviously those will have different densities and behave in different ways.
显然 它们的密度不同 行为方式也不同
So assignment five is a fairly simple assignment.
所以作业5是一个相当简单的作业
So this is just as I alluded to before.
所以这就是我之前提到的
The task here is to split the bird that you
这里的任务是把你的鸟分成两半
shoot by pressing Spacebar when it's in the bird-- the alien, when
当它在鸟的时候按空格键拍摄--外星人 当
it's in the air, press Spacebar and have it split into three.
它在空中 按空格键并将其一分为三
So you have your one that you're shooting already.
所以你已经有了一部你正在拍摄的电影
So it should just shoot off two more.
所以它应该再发射两个
One that's angled higher, one that's angled lower.
一个角度更高 一个角度更低
And all of those should be interactable with your game world.
所有这些都应该与你的游戏世界互动
And that's really it.
真的是这样
So if you can do that then it'll show that you know
因此 如果你能做到这一点 那么它将表明你知道
how to effect the Box2D game world.
如何影响Box2D游戏世界
Next time, next lecture, we'll be talking about--
下一次 下一堂课 我们将讨论--
the theme is going to be Pokemon, but we'll
主题将是精灵宝可梦 但我们将
be talking about more generally RPGs and turn-based games of that nature.
更广泛地说 是RPG和基于回合的游戏
It won't maybe necessarily look quite as pretty as this.
它可能不一定会看起来像这样漂亮
But we'll be striving for a similar over world
但我们将为类似的世界而努力
that we can walk around and then engage in fairly simple turn-based battles
我们可以四处走动 然后进行相当简单的基于回合的战斗
and stuff like that.
诸如此类的事情
And also, we'll be talking about user interfaces and things
此外 我们还将讨论用户界面和其他东西
like dialogue and stuff like that.
比如对话之类的东西
But that was it for lecture six, Angry Birds.
但第六课《愤怒的小鸟》到此为止
I'll see you next time.
下次见
Thank you.
谢谢